<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<UpdateNotes>
	<n20>
		<version>1.4.6.1</version>
		<notes>Summary\nHotfix patch for 1.4.6.\n\nGeneral Changes\n===============\n\nBewitched Alonne Sword\nHarakiri no longer true combos into itself.\nHarakiri now true combos into a Neutral R1.\nReduced motion value of Harakiri to 180.\nHarakiri now inflicts Slash damage instead of Thrust.\nCan no longer be buffed with resins/bundles/etc.\nIncreased blend of 2H neutral R2 transition to make it look less janky.\nReduced upgrade level to +5 (you will need to find or get a new +5 Bewitched Alonne Sword for this to take effect).\n\nKatanas\n-------\nIncreased recovery of running R1s into all actions by 2 frames.\n\nRings\n-----\nReduced effectiveness of Farron Ring to provide a 50% Weapon Art cost reduction.\n\nBloodborne Changes\n==================\n\nReiterpalasch\n-------------\nIncreased recovery of Graceful Salvo by into all actions by 3 frames.\nDecreased tracking of Graceful Salvo.\n\nPvE Changes\n===========\n\nHigh Wall of Lothric\n--------------------\nOverhauled lighting to appear more natural like early screenshots.\n\nCemetary of Ash\n---------------\nAdjusted lighting and time of day to match concept art.\n\nOld Wolf of Farron\n------------------\nAdjusted lighting and fog on distant terrain.\n\nSoul of Cinder\n--------------\nAdjusted hitboxes, damage and active frames.\nCan now access new spells and moves, such as Soul Greatsword and Forbidden Sun.\nCan now access new weapon forms, such as a Glaive, UGS or Lance.\nAdded a third phase that occurs when he reaches 50% HP in the second phase.\n\nStarting Classes\n----------------\nAssassin\nReduced Faith by 1.\nReduced Attunement by 1.\nIncreased Dexterity by 2.\n\nCleric\nReduced Intelligence by 1.\nIncreased Faith by 1.\n\nHerald\nReduced Intelligence by 1.\nReduce Attunement by 1.\nIncreased Strength by 2.\n\nMercenary\nIncreased Luck by 1.\nIncreased Dexterity by 2.\nReduced Attunement by 2.\nReduced Intelligence by 1.\n\nThief\nReduced Attunement by 3.\nIncreased Luck by 3.\n\nBug Fixes\n=========\nFixed various armour model masks.\nFixed bugs with Black Knights in Untended Graves.\nFixed ?GoodsInfo? appearing in the Shrine Handmaid cheat shop.\nFixed Ancient Dragon Greatshield allowing for vanilla-style HP regeneration toggling by rapidly equipping and unequipping it.\nFixed firearms gaining status effects when the mainhand weapon is buffed with Rotten Pine Resin or Carthus Rouge.\nFixed Harakiri being labelled as “Bloodlust” in the menu.\nPotentially fixed various “random” crashes in pve</notes>
	</n20>
	<n19>
		<version>1.4.6</version>
		<notes>**Summary** \nBewitched Alonne Sword\n3 new sherbet flavours \nSekiro armor sets \n4 boss reworks \nShrine Handmaid Cheat Code\nVarious balance changes\n\n-------------------------------\n**New Content** \nBewitched Alonne Sword\nRed Guard set\nSekiro set \nArmoured Warrior set\nTiel set \nPumpkin Sherbet \nFusion Sherbet \nMarshmallow Sherbet \n\n-------------------------------\n**General Changes** \n\n**Armour** \nReduced curse resistance of Vendrick’s set. \n\n**Fists** \nLifedrain is 1.5x faster for all variations (previously, the speed increase received in previous patches only applied when held in certain hands). \n\n**Greathammers** \nVordt’s Great Hammer combat art hyper armour now starts 20 frames later. \nVordt’s Great Hammer combat art extension hyper armour now starts 14 frames later. \nIncreased Hitstun of Vordt’s Great Hammer combat art extension. \n\n**Greatswords** \nChanged Moonlight Greatsword buffed visual effects to blue visual effects. \nUse of Wrath of the Gods (Wolnir’s Holy Sword) now removes 100 physical AR and adds 200 dark AR for 60 seconds. \n\n**Just Frames** \nRemoved green shader. \n\n**Miracles** \nHyper armour of Lightning Stake starts 16 frames before active frames. \nHyper armour of Wrath of the Gods starts 14 frames before active frames. \nHyper armour of Lightning Storm starts 13 frames before active frames. \nHyper armour of Lifehunt Scythe starts 11 frames before active frames. \nIncreased blend of Wrath of the Gods startup to make it smoother. \n\n**Sorceries** \nAdjusted visual and audio effects for Soul Stream. \nSpook and Aural Decoy cost 1 Attunement slot again. \nIncreased damage of Farron Flashsword by 11.6%. \n\n**Spears** \nRemoved Dexterity scaling from Dragonslayer Swordspear, now only scales with Strength and Faith. \nDragonslayer Swordspear Lightning AR no longer scales and is fixed at 80 at +5 reinforcement. Faith investment now scales Physical AR. \nIncreased Strength scaling of Dragonslayer Swordspear. \nReversed Strength and Dexterity requirements of Dragonslayer Swordspear - 22 Strength and 16 Dexterity. \nIncreased recovery of Dragonslayer Swordspear 2H running R1 into R1 by 4 frames. \n\n**Ultra Greatswords** \nIncreased motion value of Astora Greatsword 1H rolling R1 to 100.\n\n-------------------------------\n**PvE Changes** \n\n**Abyss Watchers**\nSeveral changes to attack patterns, moves and visual effects. \n\n**Black Knights** \nIncreased stamina regeneration of Black Knights to compensate for the increased frostbite stamina regeneration penalty. \n\n**Cheats** \nPerforming Point Forward, then Point Down, then Bow in front of the Shrine Handmaid opens a “cheat store” where players can buy any armour piece, weapon, spell, max level ring and consumable. \n\n**Dragonslayer Armour** \nSeveral changes to attack patterns, moves and visual effects.\n\n**Farron Keep** \nAdjusted lighting around the Old Wolf of Farron and Halfway Fortress area to improve visual fidelity and make the lighting more appealing. \n\n**Grand Archives** \nFixed the Grand Archives item key in Black Hand Gotthard’s corpse. \n\n**Irithyll of the Boreal Valley** \nAdded Hunter NPC that will drop Whirligig Saw upon death. \n\n**Nameless King** \nSeveral changes to attack patterns, moves and visual effects. \n\n**Pontiff Sulyvahn**\nSeveral changes to attack patterns, moves and visual effects.\n\n**NPCs** \nHawkwood the Deserter now wears the Undead Legion Helm during the final stage of his questline. \n\n**Soul of Cinder** \nSeveral changes to attack patterns, moves and visual effects.\n\n**Untended Graves** \nAdded glaive wielding Black Knight. \n\n-------------------------------\n**Bloodborne Changes** \nDragon transformations no longer untransform Trick Weapons. \n\n**Blade of Mercy** \nReduced forward momentum of untransformed second R2. \n\n**Holy Moonlight Sword** \nIncreased motion value of untransformed running R1 to 110. \nIncreased motion value of untransformed running R2 to 140. \nSlowed untransformed WA hyper armour startup to 12 frames. \n\n**Reiterpallasch** \nUntransformed weapon art is now a new weapon art - “insert name”. \nReduced tracking of Graceful Salvo. \nIncreased recovery of Graceful Salvo into all  actions by 5 frames. \n\n**Saw Cleaver** \nTransformed second R2 now knocks down targets. \n\n-------------------------------\n**Bug Fixes** \nFixed a bug that forced the player to experience increased recoveries after a one handed attack if they buffered a block input with a shield. \nFixed a bug that caused certain effects to trigger when equipping certain firearms, such as the Black Crystal prompt or restored HP. \nFixed backstep attacks consuming more stamina when two handing an offhand weapon with a pike in the mainhand.</notes>
	</n19>
	<n18>
		<version>1.4.5.2</version>
		<notes>Summary\nHotfixes for 1.4.5\n\nGeneral changes\n\nAxes\nIncreased forward momentum of power-stance first and third L1.\n\nGreat Hammers\nReduced motion value of Champion’s Lunge initial jump to 125.\nReduced motion value of Champion’s Lunge extension (first part) to 60.\nReduced motion value of Champion’s Lunge extension (second part) to 100.\n\nHalberds\nIncreased recovery of 1H neutral R1 to offhand L1 by 1 frame.\nDecreased recovery of power-stance first L1 slightly to enable it to consistently true combo into power-stance second L1.\n\nRings\nTripled effectiveness of Farron Ring, weapon arts now consume 75% less FP when equipped.\n\nSpears\nRemoved feints from Stance R2 (Silver Knight Spear).\n\nStarting Gifts\nAdded “None” option.\n\nThrusting Swords\nReduced auxiliary build-up of power-stance attacks.\n\nTitle Screen\nRemoved floating “™”.\n\nBloodborne changes\n\nLudwig’s Holy Blade\nReworked scaling. Is now a Strength-Faith hybrid weapon.\nChanged stat requirements to 16 Strength, 12 Dexterity and 16 Faith.\nRadiant Strike buff no longer changes AR to fire, now provides the following effects:\nAbove 50% HP: 10% damage boost + 10% Absorption boost to all elements.\nBelow 50% HP: 20% damage boost + 5% Absorption boost to all elements.\nDuration increased to 40 seconds.\n\nReiterpallasch\nRunning R1 now has the same tracking as Dark Souls 3 thrusting sword running R1.\nIncreased active frames of Running R1 by 1 frame.\nReduced critical damage to be on par with other Dark Souls 3 thrusting swords.\nIncreased FP cost of Graceful Salvo to 20.\n\nBug fixes\nFixed an item in High Wall of Lothric providing an invalid item.\nFixed Ledo’s chest piece showing skin when used on small body presets.\nFixed accessing unreleased weapons with Shriving Stones.\nFixed Reiterpallasch riposte and backstab bugs.\nFixed Reiterpallasch shieldpoke &gt; R2 following up with the spear R2.\nFixed issues with Graceful Salvo when used without sufficient FP.</notes>
	</n18>
	<n17>
		<version>1.4.5</version>
		<notes>Summary:\nUniversal feint changes\nArcane infusion adjustment\nNew \&quot;Dragon\&quot; starting class\nChanges to item and enemy placement in Firelink Shrine, High Wall of Lothric, Lothric Castle and Irithyll of the Boreal Valley.\nVarious buffs\nReiterpalasch\nNew armour sets\n\n\nNew content\n===========\n\nReiterpalasch\nConsumed King’s Knight set\nElite Lothric Knight set\nPreviously named Elite Lothric Knight set has been renamed to Royal Knight set\nGertrude’s Knights set\nAscended Gertrude’s Knights Armor\nHandmaid’s set\nAldrich Faithful set\nVanguard set\nCorporeal Forlorn Hood\nCrown of Illusions\nGravekeeper’s set\nArchive Sage’s Hat\nHigh Priestess’ set\n\n\nGeneral Changes\n===============\n\nAxes\nIncreased innate bleed of Brigand Axe to 41.\nRemoved hyper armour from Winged Knight Twinaxes 2H second R1.\nDecreased recovery of 1H neutral R1 into offhand L1 by 4 frames.\nDecreased recovery of powerstanced L1 into offensive actions by 4 frames.\nIncreased motion value of powerstanced first L1 right hand axe to 100 and decreased motion value of left hand axe to 50.\nIncreased motion value of powerstanced second L1 right hand axe to 100 and decreased motion value of left hand axe to 50.\nIncreased motion value of powerstanced third L1 right hand axe to 60 and decreased motion value of left hand axe to 30.\n\nBacksteps\nReduced locked on backstep tracking, in order to prevent being able to ravioli by performing a locked on backstep and quickly unlock to ravioli with iframes.\n\nCurved Swords\nIncreased AR of Shotel when Sharp infused.\n\nDaggers\nIncreased base damage of Tailbone Shortsword.\nLowered requirements of Tailbone Shortsword to 8 Strength and 10 Dexterity.\n\nFeints\nIntroduced a \&quot;feint limit\&quot;, that prevents feinting more than once during an attack string. Applies to all feintable attacks, including weapon arts and spells.\nSpells can only be feinted into other spells.\n\nFists\nIncreased tracking of Lifedrain.\n\nGreataxes\nSlowed hyper armour startup of Pickaxe 2H second R1 by 5 frames.\n\nGreathammers\nAdded innate poison to Large Club.\nReduced Strength requirement of Morne’s Greathammer to 30.\n\nGreatshields\nMade hyper armour on offhand bashes end 8 frames earlier.\nAdjusted Shield Strike hitboxes to be more sensical.\nIncreased forward momentum of first Shield Strike L2.\n\nGreatswords\nReduced motion value of Moonlight Greatsword R2 projectiles to 80.\nSignificantly increased Storm Ruler AR at +5 reinforcement.\nIncreased Storm Ruler durability to 65.\nIncreased AR returns from Faith for Wolnir’s Holy Sword.\nConverted a large part of Greatsword of Judgement’s Strength scaling to Dexterity scaling.\nLowered Strength requirement of Greatsword of Judgement to 14.\nIncreased AR of Twin Princes Greatsword.\n\nHalberds\nAdded new 1H second R1.\n1H running R1 &gt; R1 now follows with 1H second R1.\n1H forward R2 &gt; R1 now follows with 1H third R1.\n2H forward R2 &gt; R1 now follows with 2H second R1.\nDecreased recovery of 1H running R1 to R1 by 2 frames.\nDecreased recovery of 1H forward R2 to R1 by 6 frames.\nDecreased recovery of 2H forward R2 to R1 by 1 frame.\nRemoved second feint window from 2H neutral R2 (spin variant).\nReduced requirement of Halberd 12 Strength and 11 Dexterity.\n\nHammers\nWarcry R2s can only be feinted into Kick and second R2 - can no longer be feinted into neutral R1 and forward R2.\nIncreased innate bleed of Morning Star to 36.\n\nInfusions\nChanged Arcane infusion to pure physical AR.\n\nItems\nReduced base fire AR of Dragon Head Stone.\nIncreased Intelligence and Faith scaling of Dragon Head Stone.\n\nKatanas\nReduced motion value of 2H forward R2 to be on par with 2H running R1.\nSlowed hyper armour startup of Shinobi’s Rage R1 to 12 frames.\nHyper armour of Shinobi’s Rage R1 now ends 23 frames earlier.\nIncreased innate bleed of Chaos Blade to 46.\n\nMiracles\nIncreased startup of Lightning Stake by 3 frames.\nSped up hyper armour startup of Lightning Stake - hyper armour starts 11 frames before active frames.\nAdjusted feint window of Lightning Stake - feint window ends 9 frames before active frames.\nSped up hyper armour startup of Wrath of the Gods - hyper armour starts 10 frames before active frames.\nSped up hyper armour startup of Lightning Storm - hyper armour starts 9 frames before active frames.\nSped up hyper armour startup of Lifehunt Scythe - hyper armour starts 7 frames before active frames.\nAdjusted feint window of Lifehunt Scythe - feint window ends 5 frames before active frames.\nSlowed cast speed of Lightning Spears by 10 frames at base cast speed only.\n\nPikes\nIncreased Strength scaling of Pike.\n\nPyromancy\nReduced cost of Attunement slots for Carthus Beacon to 1.\nIncreased duration of Profuse Sweat to 120.\n\nReapers\n1H forward R2 &gt; R1 now follows with 1H third R1.\nRemoved bleed from Pontiff Knight Great Scythe.\nAdded innate frostbite to Pontiff Knight Great Scythe.\nIncreased recovery of Outrider Dash into roll, movement and block by 6 frames.\nSlowed Friede’s Great Scythe 2H neutral R1 by 7.91667%.\nAdjusted recoveries of Friede’s Great Scythe 2H neutral R1 to be on par with recoveries of a standard Reaper 2H neutral R1 except roll, movement and block, which are 1 frame slower.\n\nSorceries\nSlowed cast speed of Farron Flashsword by 6 frames at base cast speed only.\nIncreased recovery to roll, movement and block for Soul Greatsword and Old Moonlight by 10 frames.\n\nShieldpokes\nIncreased base stamina cost of Spear, Pike and Halberd shieldpoke to 39 stamina.\n\nShields (Medium and Small)\nAdjusted Shield Strike hitboxes to be more sensical.\nIncreased forward momentum of first Shield Strike L2.\n\nSpears\nIncreased base damage of Tailbone Spear.\nLowered requirements of Tailbone Spear to 10 Strength and 12 Dexterity.\nReduced Dexterity scaling of Yorshka’s Spear.\nIncreased Strength scaling of Yorshka’s Spear.\n\nStraight Swords\nIncreased bleed of Barbed Straight Sword to 38.\nIncreased recovery of Frost Blade into roll, movement and block by 6 frames.\n\nThrusting Swords\nAdded power stance.\nIncreased hitstun of 1H third R1 to straight sword stun.\nIncreased active frames of 1H neutral R1 by 2 frames.\nIncreased recovery of offhand L1 into weapon arts by 5 frames.\nRemoved hyper armour from 2H forward R2.\nReduced motion value of 2H forward R2 to be on par with 2H running R1.\n\nUltra Greatswords\nAbyss Greatsword is acquired by combining the Soul of Darkeater Midir and the Soul of the the Blood of the Wolf with Ludleth the Exiled at Firelink Shrine.\nReduced damage of Legion Stomp R2, but only on counter thrusts. Damage on normal hits is unaffected.\n\nWeapon Arts\nAttempting to use a weapon art without the required FP will trigger a “head scratch” animation akin to attempting to cast a spell without the required FP.\n\n\nBloodborne Changes\n==================\n\nBlade of Mercy\nIncreased critical damage.\nTransformed neutral R1 now has dagger hitstun.\nIncreased recovery to roll for untransformed running R1 by 3 frames.\nDecreased recovery to R1/R2 for untransformed running R1 by 6 frames.\nRemoved hyper armour from Deadly Retreat.\n\nHeavy Firearms\nRemoved hitstun from Gatling Gun.\n\nHoly Moonlight Sword\nNow acquired by combining the Moonlight Greatsword and an Arcane Gem with Ludleth the Exiled at Firelink Shrine.\n\nHunter’s Axe\nIncreased critical damage.\n\nKirkhammer\nCan now be buffed.\n\nLudwig’s Holy Blade\nCan now be buffed.\nIncreased critical damage.\nIncreased hitboxes for all attacks.\n\nRakuyo\nCan now be buffed.\nIncreased critical damage.\nReduced forward momentum of untransformed running R1.\nIncreased recovery of transformed neutral L1 to roll, movement and block by 4 frames.\nIncreased recovery of transformed second L1 to roll, movement and block by 6 frames.\nDecreased recovery of transformed third L1 to roll, movement and block by 6 frames.\nReduced motion value of transformed L1s to 80.\nAdjusted hitboxes of transformed L1s.\n\nSaw Cleaver\nIncreased critical damage.\nIncreased hitboxes for all attacks.\n\nStake Driver\nIncreased critical damage.\n\nWhirligig Saw\nIncreased critical damage.\n\n\nPvE Changes\n===========\n\nBonfires\nAllot Estus and Repair Equipment menu can be accessed from any bonfire.\n\nBurial Gifts\nTwo new burial gifts: Feast of Dung Pies and Young Dragon Ring.\n\nCemetary of Ash\nAdded or moved the following:\nFire Keeper Blindfold\nSaw Cleaver\nSoul of a Nameless Soldier\nBurial Knight Helm\nBurial Knight Armor/Gauntlets/Leggings\nLoincloth\nRusted Coin\nDragon Scale\n\nAdded or moved enemies.\n\nHigh Wall of Lothric\nAdded or moved the following as pickups or drops:\nBarrel Helm\nForlorn Set\nMagic Twinswords “Makoto”\nRoyal Lothric Knight Helm\nHunter Axe\nRock (5)\nBadgers Black Hat\nRusted Gold Coin\nIron Round Shield\nAncient Dragon Halberd\nEmber\nPriestess Ring\nCrimson Knight Set\nShortsword\nColossus Sack\nEmma’s Cowl and Garb\n\nAdded or moved enemies.\n\nIrithyll of the Boreal Valley\nAdded or moved the following as pickups or drops:\nHeide Knight Iron Mask\nHeide Knight set\nDoll set\nAlonne set\nCrown of the Dark Sun\nRock (7)\nPale Pine Bundle (2)\nGiant set\nPontiff Sulyvahn set\nValkyrie Helm\nKings set\nDark Silver set\nProof of Concord Kept\nProof of Concord Well Kept\nHuman Dreg\nMask of the Mother\nMask of the Father\nAlonne Sword placed by the silver knight archer in a corner of post-pontiff\nPenetrator set\nIrithyll Deacon Robe\nIrithyll Deacon Skirt\nPontiff Knight Great Scythe\nKirkhammer\n\nAdded or moved enemies.\n\nLothric Castle\nAdded or moved the following as pickups or drops:\nLothric Great Scythe\nLudwig’s Holy Blade\nSunlight Sherbet\nRock (10)\nElite Lothric Knight set\nBrushwood Set\nVassal set\nDragonrider set\nTengu Mask\nRoyal Knight Armor\nSacred Gem\n\nAdded or moved enemies.\n\nNPCs\nIncreased Fire Keeper status effect resistances:\n345 Bleed\n345 Frost\n315 Poison\nReplaced Half-Light’s Greatbow with Crow Quills.\nHalf-Light now wears a Loincloth.\nReplaced Sirris’ Sunless Talisman with a chime.\nOrbeck now sells Pale Pine Bundles.\nRemoved all items that were added into the worldspace from the Handmaid’s shop at the beginning of the game.\nThe Shrine Handmaiden will sell Human Pine Bundles after turning in the Mortician&apos;s Ashes.\nPatches now sells all the guns at Firelink (except rosmarinus, flamesprayer, and fist of gratia)\nThe Shrine Handmaiden will sell Rocks after turning in the Hollow’s Ashes.\nThe Shrine Handmaiden will sell Pale Pine Bundles after turning in the Prison Chief’s Ashes.\nSilver Knight Ledo will drop Ledo’s set upon death.\n\nStarting Classes\nNew starting class - Dragon.\nHerald: Removed Hunter&apos;s Ring, replaced Red Hilted Halberd with Halberd.\nMercenary: Replaced Claw with Sellsword Twinblades, replaced Caestus with Parrying Dagger. Removed Hunter Ring.\nThief: Removed Lucky Clover Ring, now wears Leather Gloves. Replaced Broken Straight Sword with Bandit&apos;s Knife. Now starts with 10 Rusted Coins, 7 Rusted Gold Coins, 3 Homeward Bones and 10 Prism Stones.\nAssassin: now starts with 5 Cracked Red Eye Orbs.\nSorcerer: now starts with a Rapier. Now has Aural Decoy and Magic Weapon attuned instead of Cast Light and Spook. Removed Scholar’s Ring.\nUpdated descriptions.\n\nUndead Settlement\nAdded the following:\nMask of Velka\n\nUntended Graves\nAdded the following:\nDragon Scale\n\nUpgrades\nAdded new upgrade material - Dragon Scales.</notes>
	</n17>
	<n16>
		<version>1.4.4</version>
		<notes>Summary\nOffensive Miracles rework. \nNew armour pieces. \nAxe “power stance”. \nNew moves added for Holy Moonlight Sword. \nNumerous balance changes and more… \n\n------------------------------\nGeneral Changes\n\nArmour\nAdded Elite Lothric Knight Armour.\nAdded Elite Lothric Knight Helmet (Open faced Lothric Knight Helmet). \nAdded Pontiff Sulyvahn&apos;s set.\nAdded Tower Knight set.\nAdded King Vendrick&apos;s set.\nAdded Mask of the Child.\nReplaced Syan Knight set with Fume Knight Raime’s set. \n(Kept Syan Knight Helm, it’s now a standalone head piece). \nReplaced Lord’s Blade set with Armor of the Vassal (Mortal Shell Harros set). \nAdded Valkyrie Helm (Elden Ring). \nAdded Heide Knight Iron Mask. \nAdded cloth physics to the Heide Knight set. \nAdded cloth physics to the Forlorn set. \nAdded cloth physics to Alonne’s Helm. \nReplaced Hunter Top Hat with standard Bloodborne Hunter Hat. \n\nAxes\nIncreased Strength scaling for Butcher Knife. \nIncreased base damage and slightly increased Strength and Dexterity scaling for Eleonora. \nSped up 2H Winged Knight Twinaxes neutral R1 to be as fast as the regular Axe R1. \nRemoved feints from second Warcry R2. \nDelayed Warcry R2 feint window by 4 frames. \nAdded a pseudo “power stance”. Equipping an axe in the left and right hand will grant new L1 attacks. Does not apply to Hand Axe and Thrall Axe. \n\nBacksteps \n&lt;30% and &lt;70% backsteps now only have iframes when executed while locked on. \nIncreased recovery of all backsteps into block by 1 frame to be on par with roll cancel. \nRestored “ravioli step”. \n\nConsumables\nIncrease Kukri motion value to 95. \nIncreased poison build up of Poison Throwing Knives. \nIncreased area of effect explosion for Firebombs and Black Firebombs (projectile variant).  \n\nClaws \nIncreased 2H neutral L1 recovery to roll and movement by 5 frames. \nReduced hitstun on Crow Talons running L1. \nRemoved feints from Raptor Flurry barring roll cancel. \n\nCurved Greatswords\nDecreased Exile Greatsword weight to 14.0. \nDecreased Exile Greatsword Dexterity requirement to 14. \nDecreased Murakumo Strength requirement to 16. \n\nCurved Swords\nRemoved feints from Prying Wedge WA R2. \nAdded frost particle effects to the Pontiff Knight Curved Sword. \n\nFists\nDark Hand now has Lifedrain in the offhand.\nSped up Lifedrain speed by 1.5x with adjusted frame data to compensate. \nFocus Blast is now unparriable. \nSlowed hyper armour startup of Focus Blast to 12 frames. \nReduced poise health of Focus Blast to Glaive poise health. \nIncreased recovery of Focus Blast into attacks by 8 frames. \n\nGestures\nAdjusted sound effects for Beg for Life. \nChanged Silent Ally icon to Deep Respect icon. \n\nGreataxes\nIncreased Faith scaling for Earth Seeker. \nIncreased hyper armour startup of 1H forward R2 to 12 frames. \nChanged counter frames of 1H forward R2 to between frames 22 and 40. \nIncreased hyper armour startup of 2H forward R2 to 13 frames. \nChanged counter frames of 2H forward R2 to between frames 21 and 40. \n\nGreathammers\nDecreased weight of Morne’s Greathammer to 18.0. \nDecreased weight of Dragon Tooth to 18.0. \nSmough’s Great Hammer R1 no longer true combos into full Executioner’s Charge. \nReduced hyper armour startup of Pickaxe 2H neutral R1 to 12 frames. \nIncreased recovery of 1H running R1 into attacks by 4 frames. \n\nGreatswords\nSped up Storm Ruler Stance R2 by 20%. \n\nHalberds\nChanged Glaive 2H second and third R1 to new moves. \nChanged 1H third R1 to a new move. \nDecreased Strength requirement of Halberd to 13. \nIncreased Dexterity requirement of Halberd to 13. \nDecreased weight of Halberd to 6.0. \nChanged counter frames of Red Hilted Halberd Stance R1 to between frames 10 to 25. \nRed Hilted Halberd Stance R1 stops tracking targets 2 frames earlier. \nIncreased recovery into all actions for Red Hilted Halberd Stance R1. \nRemoved feints from second Warcry R2. \nAdjusted visual effects on running R1. \n\nJust Frame\nAdjusted visual and sound effects on successful Just Frame. \n\nPikes\nReduced recovery into roll, block and movement by 15 frames for Lothric Warbanner WA. \n\nPvE\nIncreased bosses stamina regeneration rate to compensate for the increased stamina regeneration penalty of frostbite. \n\nPyromancy\nReduced Strength requirement of Pyromancer’s Parting Flame to 12. \nRemoved roll cancel on startup for all fireball variations and Sacred Flame to prevent roll cancelling a feint. \n\nReapers\nAdded frost particle effects to the Pontiff Knight Great Scythe.\n\nRings\nIncreased item discovery bonus for Covetous Gold Serpent Ring by 50 for all iterations. \n\nSorcery\nReduced hitstun of the staff hitbox on Farron Flashsword that occurs when casting with longer staves to straight sword stun. \nRemoved roll cancel on startup for Soul Greatsword, Soul Stream, Old Moonlight and Dark Edge to prevent roll cancelling a feint. \n\nSpears\nAdded new lightning visual effects to Dragonslayer Spear fully charged R2s. \nAdded hyper armour to 2H Dragonslayer Spear fully charged R2. \n2H Dragonslayer Spear second fully charged R2 will now launch targets. \nlower motion value of  Dragonslayers Spear fully charged R2 for balancing dmg\n1H .Dragonslayer Spear fully charged R2 now shoot lighting spear like ds1/2\nReturned “fall over” variant of Charge to Four Pronged Plow, but with significantly improved recovery and poise startup in line with other Charges. \nAdded innate bleed to Arstor’s Spear. \nIncreased base damage of Arstor’s Spear. \n\nUltra Greatswords\nIncreased tracking on Farron Greatsword second 2H R1. \nIncreased recovery to defensive actions for Earth Splitter by 5 frames. \nAdded fire particle effects to Lorian’s Greatsword. \n\nWhips\nReturned Awakening weapon art to Rose of Ariandel. \n\n------------------------------\nMiracle Changes\n\nMiracles - Lightning Spears and variations\nSped up the incantation speed of Lightning Spear variants by 5 frames. \nIncreased travel velocity of Lightning Spear.\nSlightly increased travel velocity of Great Lightning Spear. \nChanged spread time of Lightning Spear and Sunlight Spear to 170 milliseconds. (Spread time determines when hitboxes show up or are extended, refers to the close range hitbox). \nChanged spread time of Great Lightning Spear to 8.5 milliseconds. \nReduced FP cost of Lightning Spear to 17. \nReduced FP cost of Great Lightning Spear to 27. \nSunlight Spear now costs 2 attunement slots. \nReduced damage overall for all Lightning Spear variants to compensate for speed increase and other changes. \nLightning Spear variants apply a new passive effect on the proximity hitbox that lowers the opponent’s lightning absorption by 5% for 40 seconds. \nSunlight Spear applies a new passive effect on the projectile hitbox that lowers the opponent’s lightning absorption by 15% for 60 seconds. \n\nMiracles - Healing and Buffs \nIncreased health recovery of healing miracles by 20%. \nIncreased duration of rally secondary effect of healing miracles up to 30 seconds for Heal Aid, Heal and Med Heal and up to 40 seconds for Great Heal and Soothing Sunlight. \nReduced stamina cost of Sacred Oath to 60. \n\nMiracles - Other\nAdded hyper armour to Lightning Storm, Divine Pillars of Light, Lightning Stake, Lifehunt Scythe and Wrath of the Gods. \nRemoved feints from Lightning Storm. \nReduced immunity granted after being hit by one Divine Pillar of Light to 100 milliseconds. \nDivine Pillars of Light now has 100% shield pierce. \nDivine Pillars of Light now spawns 12 additional pillars in a circle around the caster. \nIncrease travel velocity of all pillars. \nIncreased hitbox size of all pillars. \nSped up Wrath of the Gods by 1 frame to make it as fast as Lightning Storm. \nWrath of the Gods now only uses one attunement slot. \nIncreased active frames of Wrath of the Gods to 400 milliseconds. \nRemoved roll cancel on startup for Lightning Spear variations, Gnaw variations, Lightning Stake, Wrath of the Gods, Lifehunt Scythe and Way of White Corona to prevent roll cancelling a feint. \n\nMiracles - Talismans\nHallowed Earth- New weapon art for Sunlight Talisman, Talisman, Saint’s Talisman, White Hair Talisman and Sunless Talisman.\nHallowed Earth: Create a small area of effect. When stood within the area, benefit from the following blessings: \nIncreased poise by 18% \nMiracles cost 20% less FP to cast.\nIncreased Miracle spell boost by 5%. \nIncreased stamina regeneration by 10/s. \nAdded passive FP regeneration at a rate of 0.5/s. \nEach area of Hallowed Earth lasts 2 minutes from being cast. Opponents who stand within the area lose 10 HP per second.\nRenamed Unfaltering Prayer to Holy Gale to better match it’s effect. \nPoise health of the aforementioned miracles now varies based on which Talisman is used to cast it. \nSunlight = Great Hammer\nTalisman and Canvas = Curved Greatsword\nSunless = Greatsword\nSaint = Hammer\n\n--------------------------------------\nBloodborne Changes\n\nBeast Cutter\nMoves where the chain whip is extended are no longer parriable. \nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nReplaced counter frames with instability frames for untransformed jumping attack. \nChanged visual effects applied on hit. \nImproved hitboxes on all R1s. \nReduced pushback on untransformed R1s. \nAdded hyper armour to backstep R1s and R2s. \nAdded hyper armour to running R2s. \n\nBlade of Mercy\nIncreased hitboxes for all moves. \nStandardised recovery of all L1s into R1s and vice versa. \nReduced knockback on all moves by 50%. \nFirst and fourth R1s have negative knockback (pull the opponent closer). \nIncreased Intelligence scaling. \nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nImproved tracking of all transformed R1s and L1s. \n\nFirearms\nAdjusted Hunter Pistol to fire at the same speed as the Evelyn. \nAdjusted Blunderbuss to fire at the same speed as Ludwig’s Rifle. \nPiercing Rifle spawns the bullet at frame 10, up from frame 9. \nChanged rolling attack bullet. \nIncreased hitstun in PvE. \nAdjusted all Guns bullet VFX. \n\nFist of Gratia \nIncreased motion value of running L1 to 140. \nIncreased motion value of rolling L1 to 126. \nReduced stamina cost of running and rolling L1 to 25 stamina.  \n\nHeavy Firearms\nAdjusted Gatling Gun bullet VFX,and added steam when finish shoot. \nReduced Gatling Gun tracking. \nfourth Gatling Gun shots have no hitstun. \nDelayed bullet spawn of Cannon and Church Cannon by 2 frames. \nSpeed up the initial stagger hitbox of Cannon and Church Cannon by 1 frame. \nIncreased the gap between the initial stagger hitbox of Cannon and Church Cannon and the bullet to 15 frames. \nAdded a second initial stagger hitbox for Cannon and Church Cannon to prevent combos. \nReduced stamina consumption of Cannon and Church Cannon to 100 stamina. \nReduced recovery to roll of Cannon by 12 frames to be on par with Church Cannon. \n\nHoly Moonlight Sword\nAdded new custom transformed neutral L1. \nAdded new custom R1 and R2 follow ups to Moonlight Fury. \nAdjusted rolling R1 animation and frame data. \nImproved damage of transformed fully charged R2s. \nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nInputting an R1 after rolling R1 and running R1 now follows up with second R1. \nincreased recovery of transformed rolling L1 into Moonlight Fury. \nChanged transformed running L1 to Dark Souls 3 Greatsword running R1. \nAdded greatsword hyper armour to transformed rolling and running R1. \nAdjusted feint windows of transformed running R1 and running L1 to be in line with Dark Souls 3 Greatsword running R1 feint windows. \n\nHunter’s Axe \nReplaced transformed running L1 with Dark Souls 3 Halberd 2H running R1. \nRemoved the ability for transformed running R1 to be feinted into a neutral R1. \nSped up untransformed neutral R1 to 1.08x speed. \nIncreased recoveries into all actions slightly in line with the speed change. \nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nSped up untransformed backstep R1 by 1 frame and increased active frames by 1 frame. \nIncreased hitbox size of transformed fourth R1. \nReduced knockback for transformed first and third R1. \nSlowed hyper armour startup of transformed WA to 14 frames. \nIncreased recovery to roll, move and block of transformed WA by 3 frames. \nDecreased recovery to R1 for untransformed backstep R1 by 1 frame. \nIncreased recovery to R2 for untransformed backstep R1 by 1 frame. \nIncreased hitstun of untransformed backstep R1 to straight sword stun. \nReduced pushback of untransformed jump attack. \n\nKirkhammer \nSignificantly improved recovery into all actions of transformed second R2 to be the same as first R2. \nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nSlightly increased recovery of transformed rolling R1 and L1 into Crushing Rain. \nAdd poise on transformed running/rolling r1 same value as Dark Souls 3Great hammer run r1\nAdded hyper armour to transformation followup attacks. \n\nLudwig’s Holy Blade\nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nAdd poise on running/rolling r1 same as Dark Souls 3 Ultra Greatsword run r1\nReplaced transformed running L1 with Dark Souls 3 Ultra Greatsword running R1. \nSecond l1 has nerfed stun in Pve\nAdded hyper armour to transformation followup attacks. \n\nRakuyo\nChanged both running R1s and transformed running L1 to different running attacks from Bloodborne. \n\nSaw Cleaver\nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \n\nStake Driver\nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nImproved hitboxes for all attacks. \nReduced pushback for all R1s. \nAdded Glaive poise health to both transformation attacks. \nAdded Glaive poise health to transformed neutral R2. \n\nWhirligig Saw \nImproved tracking and cancel windows on backstep attacks, Charged R2s, transform attacks, third R1s and fourth R1s. \nReduced pushback on untransformed R1s. \nDecreased recovery of Spin Bash first part into extension by 2 frames. \nImproved Spin Bash active frames. \nDecreased recovery of Spin Bash into R1 by 6 frames. \nImproved window to buffer a weapon art during untransformed running R1 by 10 frames. \nReduced pushback of untransformed running R1. \nUntransformed WA R2 now knocks down targets. \nImproved hyper armour frames of untransformed WA R2 to be on par with regular Spin Sweep. \n\n------------------------\nBug Fixes \nFixed buffered Just Frames for Bare Fists, Harald Curved Greatsword, Follower Javelin, Follower Shield, Ethereal Oak Shield and Dragonhead Greatshield. \nFixed visual bug with Saint’s Dress. \nFixed offhand recovery bug with transformed Beast Cutter.\nFixed visual bugs with transformed Beast Cutter. \nFixed an issue where lightning damage played the wrong sound. \nFixed an issue where throwing knives played the wrong sound. \nFixed bug that allowed guns to build up status effects by buffing the mainhand weapon with a resin. \nFixed Broadsword Stance R2 performing the Red Hilted Halberd Stance R2.\nFixed bug that caused Heavy Firearms to deal no damage to certain enemies in PvE. \nFixed Fist of Gratia triggering in the offhand when performing a two handed backstep L1. \nRemoved an SpEffect from Blade of Mercy that made them confer three attunement slots. \nFixed Salvation Axes gaining less Strength scaling when Sharp infused at +10 compared to +9. \nFixed model masks on Binded Set, Bone Ash Set, Doll Set, Gloom set, Demon of Hatred Head, etc.\nFixed various issues Lapp’s Helm had with new armours. \nFixed issue with Crescent Axe going into t-pose. \nFixed Winged Knight Halberd making bugged sounds. \nFixed a spelling error in the Silver Knight Straight Sword description. \nFixed a spelling error in the Silver Knight Spear description. \nFixed Torch having no kick. \nFixed bug that prevented certain firearms from not consuming FP under certain conditions. \nFixed visual bugs with Burial Knight Gauntlets. \nFixed texture issue with Ludwig’s Rifle. \nFixed visual bug that caused the fire damage visual effect to trigger on magic damage hits. \nFixed sound effect bug with Beast Cutter weapon art. \nResolved a bug where firearms paired with Dark Souls 3 weapons did the running shot after backstep but neutral shot when paired with Bloodborne weapons. Now all firearms perform the neutral shot after backstep.</notes>
	</n16>
	<n15>
		<version>1.4.3.1</version>
		<notes>**General Changes** \n\n**Summary**\nDrastic adjustments to firearms. \nSeveral bug fixes. \n\n**Armour**\nBlack Dragon set now shares the stats of the Dragonscale set. \nAdded Chinese translation to item descriptions. \nAdded missing descriptions to the Doll and Graveguard sets. \nAdded Monk Straw Hat to Shrine Handmaiden shop. \n\n**Locations\nUpdated Firelink Shrine lighting. \n\n-------------------------------------------------------------------------------\n\nBloodborne Changes\n\n*Fist of Gratia**\nIncreased hitstun in PvE. \n\n**Firearms - General**\nFirearms can no longer perform headshots. \nAll firearms now deal standard damage (excluding cannons, which deal strike). \nFirearms (excluding Heavy Firearms and Sprayers) now perform similar poise damage to crossbow bolts. \nIncreased move and offhand recovery for all firearms (excluding Heavy Firearms and Sprayers) by 10 frames. \nIncreased recovery of firearm shots into consecutive shots by 10 frames. \nFirearms now display how much FP they consume. \n\n**Heavy Firearms**\nGatling Gun can now be fired while walking. \nChanged Gatling to consume 2 FP every time the shot fire is heard.\n\n**Pistols**\nSlowed down neutral and rolling L1 to 0.77x. \nReduced knockback on Repeating Pistol to 0.3.\n\n**Rifles**\nSlowed down neutral and rolling L1 of Blunderbuss and Ludwig’s rifle to 0.56x.\nSlowed down neutral and rolling L1 of Piercing Rifle to 0.77x. \nReduced knockback on Blunderbuss and Ludwig’s Rifle to 0.05. \nRemoved tracking from Blunderbuss and Ludwig’s Rifle. \nReduced hitstun of Piercing Rifle to dagger stun. \nAdded 25% shield pierce to Piercing Rifle. \nReduced knockback on Piercing Rifle to 0.6. \n\n**Sprayers**\nDrastically reduced motion value of Rosmarinus at all ranges. \nSlightly increased motion value of Flamesprayer at all ranges to make it comparable to Rosmarinus. \nRemoved faith requirement from Rosmarinus.\nChanged Flamesprayer and Rosmarinus to consume 5 FP every time the bullet is fired, which is 4 times per animation equaling to the previous 20 FP cost. \n\n**Holy Moonlight Sword**\nReduced FP cost of Moonlight Fury to 18. \nReduced stamina cost of untransformed second R2 to 50 stamina. \nIncreased recovery of transformed second R1 to R1 by 7 frames \nIncreased recovery to block to be the same as move cancel.\nTransformed Neutral L1s now perform Neutral R1s.\nReduced backstab motion value to be the same as a regular greatsword. \n\n**Beast Cutter**\nImproved active frames and tracking for transformed R1s: \nR1 (1): 19~29 active frames, tracks for 2 additional frames.\nR1 (2): 17~27 active frames, tracks for 2 additional frames.\nR1 (3): 20~31 active frames, tracks for 2 additional frames.\nR1 (4): 19~29 active frames, tracks for 4 additional frames. \n\nUT &gt; T : 26~35 active frames, tracks for 4 additional frames \nT &gt; UT: Hyper armour now starts at frame 12. Recovery to R1 reduced by 5 frames. Improved tracking. \n\n**Kirkhammer**\nDecreased poise damage of Crushing Rain.\nIncreased hitstun in PvE of untransformed R1s. \n\n**Saw Cleaver**\nIncreased hitstun in PvE of untransformed R1s. \n\n**Ludwig’s Holy Blade**\nIncreased hitstun in PvE of untransformed R1s. \nRemoved knockdown from transformed charged R2s in PvE. \n\n------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------\n\n**Bug Fixes**\nFixed several masking issues with armours. \nFixed cannons being able to trigger Iron Flesh effect. \nFixed Holy Moonlight Sword dealing zero damage on riposte. \nFixed Church Cannon dealing zero damage to players. \nFixed Gatling Gun being unable to go into hitstun. \nFixed issue with guns doing double damage due to spawning twice the intended shots, and by extension fixed Blunderbuss inflicting very high bleed. \nFixed a developer version of Hunter’s Axe being accessible by infusing the live version with a Shriving Stone. \nFixed Dragon Bone Smasher Running R1 going into a Warcry R2.\nFixed an issue with Saw Cleaver Rolling R2 animation.</notes>
	</n15>
	<n14>
		<version>1.4.3</version>
		<notes>Summary: \nSeveral new Bloodborne firearms. \nTwo new trick weapons. \n160 pieces of armour. \nJust Frame mechanic. \nNumerous balance changes. \nStat changes, such as more fp from attunement.\nBloodborne weapons can now be tricked while moving.\nChanged lighting in some areas.\n\nNew Additions\n-----------------------\n\nNew mechanic - Just Frame\nAfter performing an R1, time the input of the second R1. If done correctly (evidenced by a visual queue), the followup R1 will restore some stamina to the user. \n\nWeapons\nBeast Cutter\nHoly Moonlight Sword\nFist of Gratia\n\nBlunderbuss\nCannon\nChurch Cannon\nEvelyn\nFlamesprayer\nGatling Gun \nHunter Pistol\nLudwig’s Rifle\nPiercing Rifle\nRepeating Pistol\nRosmarinus \n\nItems\nRock\n\nHeadpieces\nBadger&apos;s Black Hat \nBarrel Helmet\nCorvian Knight Helm\nCrab Helmet\t\nCrown of Filianore \nCrown of the Dark Sun\nDemon of Hatred Head\nDirty Colossus Sack \nGenichiro Helmet \nGold Ardeo \nGyoubu&apos;s Helm\nMask of the Child\nMask of the Father\nMask of the Mother \nMensis Cage\nMonk Mask\nMonk Straw Hat \nNightjar Mask \nOkami Mask\nOld Monk Wrapping\nPriest Mask \nPygmy Crown\nSeven Spear Helmet\nTengu Mask \n\nFull armour sets\nBinded \nBrushwood \nDark Silver \nGloom \nPenetrator \n\nBlack Cleric \nChester’s \nGiant \nGolem \nGreat Lord \nLord’s Blade  \n\nAlonne \nAurous \nBlack Dragon \nDragonrider \nForlorn \nHeide Knight \nImperious \nLoyce \nMirror Knight\nPursuer \nRampart Golem  \nSmelter Demon \nSyan\nVengarl \n\nBone Ash\nCainhurst \nDoll \nGraveguard\nHunter\n\nLedo\n\nGeneral Changes\n--------------------------\n\nStarting Classes\nIncreased Dexterity of Sorcerer to 12. \nReduced Intelligence of Sorcerer to 22. \n\nAttributes\nIncreased Focus Point gain per level of Attunement by 1.5x.\nIncreased item discovery gain per level of Luck. \n\nBacksteps\nReduced iframes by 2 frames. \nIncreased recovery to roll/block/movement by 2 frames (now on par with rolling). \n\nGestures\nReplaced some gestures with Bloodborne variants: \nPoint Forward - BB Point Forward \nWave - BB Wave \nJoy - Approval\nRejoice - Joyful\nDignified Bow - Respect\nPrayer - BB Prayer\nProstration - Beg for Life\nSilent Ally - Deep Respect\n\nUnmannered Bow can now be bought from the Shrine Handmaiden after killing the Exiles. \nLord of Cinder gesture can be used to activate the reallocate stats menu (unlimited uses). \nLord of Cinder gesture changed to “Make Contact”. \nMake Contact can be acquired, through, well, here&apos;s a clue:\n\n\&quot;Though a sudden fright, it&apos;s not one to fight. Give it a pray instead of a slay!\&quot;\n\nLocations\nAdjusted lighting at Cemetary of Ash, Catacombs of Carthus, Demon Ruins and Old Wolf of Farron.\nMinor map edits to High Wall of Lothric and Catacombs of Carthus.\n\nMiscellaneous\nIncreased recovery of wall bounce animations into roll by 6 frames. \nUpdated Sherbet icons. \nFixed Soul consumable icons being exported in the wrong format. \n\nNPCs\nReduced Fire Keeper HP to 9999. \n\n\nWeapon Changes\n---------------------------\n\nClaws\nIncreased recovery to roll on Leaping Slash by 7 frames. \nChanged hitstun on Leaping Slash. If both claws connect, it will only combo to one neutral L1s. If only the right hand claw connects, it will combo to two neutral L1s. \n\nCurved Greatswords\nRemoved R2 &gt; WA feint.\n\nDaggers\nDecreased motion value of Dagger, Mailbreaker and Brigand Twindaggers riposte to 396. \nIncreased recovery of 2H R1 into WA by 5 frames. \n\nFists\nReduced Strength scaling on Bare Fists at sub-40 Strength investment and increased Strength scaling at post-40 Strength investment. \n\nGreataxes\nRemoved R2 &gt; WA feint.\n\nGreathammers\nRemoved R2 &gt; WA feint.\nReduced feint window on Ledo’s Great Hammer R2s by 4 frames. \nChanged 2H rolling R1 to Astora Greatsword rolling attack. \nReduced motion value of 2H rolling R1 to 85. \n\nGreatshields\nAdded “Shield Strike” weapon art to Lothric Knight Greatshield, Stone Greatshield and Twin Dragon Greatshield. \n\nGreatswords\nUpdated Moonlight Greatsword model. \nUpdated Loyce Greatsword item icon. \n\nHalberds\nDecreased recovery of 2H R1 into R1 by 2 frames for Ancient Dragon Halberd to enable more consistent true combos. \nAdjusted Crucifix of the Mad King weapon art follow up. L2 &gt; R2 will perform the roar, L2 &gt; R1 will spawn the dark bomb. \n\nHammers\nIncreased recovery of 2H R1 into R2 by 5 frames for hammers. \nIncreased recovery of 2H R1 into R2 by 2 frames for clubs. \nSlowed hyper armour startup on 2H forward R2 to 13 frames. \n\nKatanas\nRemoved feints from Shinobi’s Rage. \nUpdated Magic Twinswords “Makoto” item icon. \n\nPikes\nBackstep into R1 will no longer perform the running R1. \nDecreased tracking on running R1. \nIncreased motion value to 100 on Greatlance second R2. \nAdjusted Pike item description, correcting an inaccuracy about it being the longest melee weapon. \n\nReapers\nRemoved hyper armour from Pontiff Knight Great Scythe third R1. \nElfriede&apos;s Stance R1 chains and R2 now consume FP. \nElfriede’s Stance now takes 26 frames before invisibility takes effect. \nElfriede&apos;s Stance invisibility effect no longer persists when out of stamina. \nReturned Friede’s Great Scythe second and third 2H R1s to vanilla speed. \nIncreased recovery of Friede’s Great Scythe first 2H R1 to L2 by 12 frames. \n\nRings\nReduced Hornet Ring riposte motion values by 10%. \n\nShields\nAdded “Shield Strike” weapon art to Lothric Knight Shield, Round Shield, East-West Shield and Porcine Shield. \n\nSmall Shields\nAdded “Shield Strike” weapon art to Ghru Rotshield and Elkhorn Round Shield. \n\nSorcery\nReduced FP cost of Farron Dart to 0. \n\nSpears\nRemoved R2 &gt; Stance feint from Silver Knight Spear. \nRemoved Stance R2 &gt; R1 feint from Silver Knight Spear. \nRemoved R2 &gt; Spin Sweep feint from Partizan. \nRemoved R1/L1 feint from Drang Twinspears Charge.\nReduced motion value of thunderbolt on Lightning Charge (Dragonslayer Spear) to 75. \nAdjusted Yorshka’s Spear item description to make the weapon art effect clearer. \nUpdated Silver Knight Spear item icon. \n\nStraight Swords\nRemoved feints from Lightning Storm. \nRemoved R2 &gt; Stance feint from 2H Lothric Knight Sword. \nRemoved Stance R2 &gt; R2 feint.\nIncreased recovery of 1H running R1 &gt; R1 by 4 frames. \nUpdated Silver Knight Straight Sword item icon. \n\nUltra Greatswords\nDecreased recovery of vertical 2H R1 into R1 by 2 frames to enable more consistent true combos. \nDragon Bone Smasher now has the UGS 1H forward R2.\nReduced poise health of Dragon Bone Smasher from Greathammer to UGS. \nIncreased pushback on block for Dragon Bone Smasher running R1.\nAdded an effect to Dragon Bone Smasher that causes Kicks after running R1s to be slightly delayed (does not affect recovery into neutral R1 or other attacks).\nUpdated Dragon Bone Smasher item icon. \nUpdated Abyss Greatsword item icon. \nAdjusted Fume Ultra Greatsword item description, correcting an inaccuracy about it being the heaviest ultra greatsword. \n\nWhips\nRemoved R2 &gt; WA feint.\nSlightly sped up R1s and increased active frames: \n\nOne Handed:\n(1) 25 (start up) to 34\n(2) 25 (start up) to 34\n(3) 23 (start up) to 34\n\nTwo Handed:\n(1) 24 (start up) to 32\n(2) 26 (start up) to 34\n(3) 24 (start up) to 32\n\n\nBloodborne\n---------------------------------\n\nHolding down Triangle/Y or the keyboard equivalent will result in a transformation attack. \nPressing Triangle/Y or the keyboard equivalent will result in a neutral transformation. \nTrick Weapons now have Bloodborne idle and movement animations. \n\nBlade of Mercy\nAdjusted visual effects.\nReduced knock back on transformed R1s. \nTransformed kick now pulls targets towards the wielder. \nDeceased recovery of transformed kick into attacks by 4 frames. \nIncreased Intelligence scaling. \nIncreased motion value sixth, seventh and eighth R1s. \nReduced weight to 2.5. \nRolling L1 now performs Bloodborne side dash R1. \n\nHunter’s Axe\nReduced Dexterity scaling. \nIncreased Strength scaling. \nUntransformed second R1 frame data matches original Bloodborne frame data. \nTransformed Kick and Backstep R1 into R2/Jump Attack combos no longer receive instability bonus.\nReduced weight to 12. \nReduced pushback on untransformed second R1. \nIncreased active frames of untransformed backstep R1 to 5 frames. \nAdjusted motion value and hitstun of untransformed backstep R1 to be the same as neutral R1. \nAdjusted hyper armour frames of untransformed backstep R2 to start at frame 15 and end at frame 29. \nImproved tracking of untransformed backstep R2 by 8 frames. \nRemoved counter frames from untransformed Jumping Attack (still has instability frames). \nImproved tracking of untransformed Jumping Attack by 2 frames. \nImproved tracking of UT &gt; T transformation attack by 5 frames. \nHyper armour of T &gt; UT transformation attack now starts 7 frames earlier. \nImproved recovery of L1s into consecutive L1s for more consistent true combos. \n\nRecovery changes: \nDecreased recovery to R1 of untransformed Jumping Attack by 8 frames. \nDecreased recovery of UT &gt; T transformation attack to R1/R2 by 2 frames. \nDecreased recovery to R1 of T &gt; UT transformation attack by 1 frame. \nDecreased recovery into R1 of untransformed backstep R1 by 3 frames. \nDecreased recovery into weapon switch (1h/2h input) by 3 frames on untransformed second R1. \nRemoved all R1 &gt; L1 true combos barring first R1 &gt; L1. \n\nAdjusted R1 follow ups: \nUntransformed rolling R1, backstep R1 and running R2 now follows with the second R1. \nUntransformed running R1 now follows with the third R1. \nUntransformed R2 and backstep R2 now follows with fourth R1. \nT &gt; UT transformation attack now follows with the third R1. \n\nAdjusted R2 follow ups: \nT &gt; UT transformation attack now follows with the second R2. \nUntransformed third R1 now follows with the second R2. \n\nKirkhammer\nReduced weight to 12.5. \nUT &gt; T transformation attack can now true combo into Neutral R1. \nUT &gt; T transformation attack can no longer true combo into Neutral L1 and Neutral R2. \n\nLudwig’s Holy Blade\nReduced weight to 12.0. \nImproved tracking of transformed Neutral L1. \nUT &gt; T transformation attack can now true combo into Neutral L1. \n\nRakuyo\nReduced hitboxes on running attacks. \n\nSaw Cleaver\nDecreased recovery into consecutive attacks on third and fourth R1s. \nFourth R1 is now followed by the third. \nIncreased motion value on third and fourth R1s. \nIncreased hitstun on untransformed moveset in PvE. \nReduced weight to 7.5. \n\nStake Driver\nDecreased recovery into consecutive attacks on third and fourth R1s. \nFourth R1 is now followed by the third. \nIncreased motion value on third and fourth R1s. \nReduced weight to 5.0. \n\nWhirligig Saw\nReduced Dexterity scaling. \nIncreased Strength scaling. \nReduced stamina consumption of untransformed R2. \nIncreased Strength requirement to 17. \nReduced hitstun of transformed L2 in PvE. \nReduced weight to 12.\nHyper armour on T &gt; UT transformation attack begins at frame 35 and ends at frame 44. \nIncreased active frames by 1 frame for untransformed first and third R1s. \n\nRecovery changes for untransformed moveset:\nDecreased recovery to R1 by 15 frames on R2. \nDecreased recovery to R2 by 8 frames on R2. \nDecreased recovery to R1 by 3 frames on backstep R1. \nDecreased recovery to R1 by 10 frames on backstep R2. \nDecreased recovery to R1 by 4 frames on running R2. \nDecreased recovery to R1 by 5 frames on Jumping Attack. \nDecreased recovery to R2 and switch by 4 frames on second R1. \nDecreased recovery to switch by 10 frames for R2. \nDecreased recovery to switch by 8 frames for running R2. \n\nAdjusted R1 follow ups for untransformed moveset: \nBackstep R1 now follows with third R1. \nBackstep R2 now follows with second R1. \nRunning R1 now follows with third R1. \nRunning R2 now follows with fourth R1. \nRolling R1 now follows with second R1. \nRolling R2 now follows with first R1. \nNeutral R2 now follows with first R1. \nCharged R2 now follows with second R1. \nFourth R1 now follows with third R1. \n\n\nBug Fixes\n----------------\nFixed Rakuyo WA having bugged recovery into weapon switch.\nFixed animation issues with Saw Cleaver running attacks. \nPerfect Block will now stack with Magic Shield and Great Magic Shield. \nFixed Giant Door Shield having no hitbox on Second R1. \nFixed Exile Greatsword not being parryable.\nFixed Executioner Greatsword Stomp stamina issue.\nOld Moonlight feints don&apos;t regen stamina anymore.\nFixed transformed trick weapon plunge attacks. \nFixed transformed Hunter’s Axe not having a hitbox on backstab whiff.\nFixed charged R2 skip issue with Hunter’s Axe.  \nFixed Stake driver not using weapon animations.</notes>
	</n14>
	<n13>
		<version>1.4.2</version>
		<notes>General Changes\n--------------------------- \n\nPvE\nIncreased hitstun (only in PvE) of: \nHunter’s Axe R2s.\nStake Driver transformed charged R2.\nAll Kirkhammer and Ludwig’s Holy Blade attacks.\n\nInfusions\nRenamed Blessed infusion to Sacred. \nRenamed Simple infusion to Arcane. \nAdded various benefits to +10 Raw infused weapons: \n20% poise damage increase  \n40% stamina damage increase \n25% stability increase \n\nFirekeeper\nDisabled NG+ scaling. \nIncreased all flat defences to 140. \nIncreased all absorptions to 30%.\nIncreased HP to 99999. \n\nArmour\nTransferred Pyromancer Crown passive effect to Old Sages Blindfold. \nRenamed Dingy Hood to Fire Keeper Blindfold. \n\nStraight Swords\nReduced stamina damage by 50% on 2H Broadsword and Shortsword R1s.  \nIncreased recovery of 2H Broadsword, Shortsword and Broken Straight Sword running R1 to R1 by 2 frames. \nRemoved hyper armour from Broadsword variant of Stance R2. \nReduced physical AR of Silver Knight Straight Sword by 26 AR. \nReduced stamina damage of Silver Knight Straight Sword WA by 66%. \nIncreased recovery of Silver Knight Straight Sword R2 to R1. \nRemoved feint from Ringed Knight Straight Sword WA R1. \n\nThrusting Swords\nIncreased recovery of offhand L1s into mainhand R2s. \nIncreased recovery of Shield Splitter into R1, preventing it from true comboing. \nIncreased the recovery of running R1 to R1 to its vanilla value. \n\nCurved Swords\nReduced stamina damage by 50% on 2h fast Curved Sword R1s. \nIncreased recovery of 2h first R1 by 2 frames. \n\nDaggers\nIncreased recovery to roll by 2 frames. \n\nGreatswords\nIncreased hyper armour startup on Sacred Light and Flame to 10 frames. \n\nPikes\nIncreased recovery of 1H and 2H running R1 to 14 frames. \n\nHalberds\nReduced feint window on Black Knight Glaive 2H R2. \nRemoved 2H R1-R1 unlocked triple hit combo from Ancient Dragon Halberd. \n\nCharge Weapon Art\nRemoved R1 feint from all forms of Charge. \n\nUltra Greatswords\nReduced poise health of Fume Ultra Greatsword to be on par with other Ultra Greatswords. \nReduced motion value of 1H forward R2 to 80. \nIncreased recovery of all attacks into L2/WA. \nRemoved damage reduction from Stomp. \nRemoved 2H R1-R1 unlocked triple hit combo from Cathedral Knight Greatsword, Greatsword, Black Knight Greatsword. \nIncreased recovery of one handed running R1 into R1. \nRemoved R2 feint from all forms of Stomp WA R2. \n\nGreataxes\nIncreased recovery of 2H running R1 to R2 by 2 frames.\nRemoved R2 feint from Demonic Flare, Falling Bolt and Earthen Wrath. \nRestored running R1 to R1 feint. \n\nGreat Hammers\nIncreased hyper armour startup on Morne’s Rage and Quake to 10 frames. \nRemoved R2 feint from Morne’s Rage, Molten Perseverance and Quake. \n\nPyromancy\nReduced Fire Surge AR by 10%. \nRemoved reset stun from Chaos Bed Vestiges. \nReduced Black Flame, Great Combustion and Combustion hitstun to dagger stun. \nDecreased speed of Boulder Heave cast by 10 frames. \n\nSorcery\nFeint window on Soul Greatsword and Old Moonlight now ends 5 frames earlier. \n\nBloodborne Changes\n--------------------------------\n\nBloodborne weapons are now listed under the weapon class of “Trick Weapon”. \n\nBlade of Mercy\nIncreased transformed R2 hitstun to ultra stun. \nIncreased Deadly Retreat hitstun to ultra stun. \nUntransformed R2 cancels 2 frames faster to transformation. \nUntransformed charged R2 cancels 11 frames faster to transformation.\nAdjusted visual and sound effects for R1s, L1s, R2s and transformations.  \nReduced range of Deadly Retreat to match new visual. \n\nHunter’s Axe\nReplaced untransformed forward R1 with Gundyr Kick. \nIncreased poise damage when transformed to reflect two handed bonus. \nRemoved “bounce” hitbox from untransformed moveset. \nIncreased recovery of WA to attacks. \n\nKirkhammer\nAdded L1 feint to Crushing Rain. \nRemoved R1 feint from running R1. \nIncreased poise damage to two handed Ultra Greatsword level. \nIncreased poise health to Great Hammer level. \nIncreased tracking on transformed R2. \nDecreased knockback distance on untransformed R1s. \nChanged untransformed running R1 frame data to be the same as Straight Sword running R1. \nUntransformed backstep R2 and charged R2 cancel faster to transformation. \nUntransformed neutral transformation cancels faster to R1 and L1. \nIncreased hitstun on untransformed charged R2 and backstep R2. \nAdjusted sound and visual effects for transformed followup R1s. \n\nLudwig’s Holy Blade\nIncreased poise damage to two handed Ultra Greatsword level. \nRemoved R1 feint from running R1. \nIncreased poise health to Ultra Greatsword level. \nDecreased knockback distance on untransformed R1s. \nChanged untransformed running R1 frame data to be the same as Straight Sword running R1. \nUntransformed backstep R2 and charged R2 cancel faster to transformation. \nUntransformed neutral transformation cancels faster to R1 and L1. \nIncreased hitstun on untransformed charged R2 and backstep R2. \nIncreased range on transformed moveset. \n\nRakuyo\nRemoved R2s being able to feint into R2s. \n\nSaw Cleaver\nDecreased knockback distance on transformed R1s.\n\nStake Driver\nIncreased Strength scaling AR bonus. \nIncreased startup of backstep charged R2 by 7 frames. \nDecreased stamina cost of untransformed R2 by 10 stamina. \nAdjusted sound effects for R1s and jumping attacks. \nReduced tracking on transformed second R2. \nReduced stamina cost on untransformed WA. \n\nWhirligig Saw\nAdjusted transformed attacks to have Glaive poise damage. \nIncreased tracking on untransformed running R1. \n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\nFixed R2 chains occurring in the improper order after transforming a Bloodborne weapon. \nFixed certain attack chains repeating on Bloodborne weapons. \nFixed Blade of Mercy not having a no FP version of its WA. \nFixed the followup R1 from transforming Kirkhammer from sword to hammer form displaying the incorrect animation. \nFixed issues with Bloodborne weapon R2s when bouncing off walls. \nFixed the transformed running L1 on Ludwig’s Holy Blade not having a hitbox.\nFixed Stake Driver WA being able to be roll cancelled.</notes>
	</n13>
	<n12>
		<version>1.4.1</version>
		<notes>New Additions\n---------------------\n\nNew Ring: Ring of the Unburdened \n\nDesigned to allow fast rolling/dashing in heavier armour combinations with relevant defense penalties that would accompany making a fast roll build. \n\n          - Replaces Morne&apos;s Ring (Uses the same ID and is acquired in the same place) \n          - Increases equipment load by 230%. \n          - Reduces physical absorption by 40%. \n          - Reduces elemental absorption by 20%. \n          - Reduces poise by 30%.\n\n- Updated icon image for Clover Ring. \n\nGeneral Changes\n-------------------------\n\n- Removed tracking from backsteps. \n\nGeneral Bloodborne Changes\n- Increased recovery to movement and blocking on all untransformed attacks. \n- Increased tracking on kicks/forward R1s (except transformed Hunter’s Axe). \n- Gave dashes similar frame data to vanilla fast rolls. \n- Trick weapons can no longer be buffed. \n- Removed hyperarmor from untransformed jumping attacks. \n- Removed counter frames and replaced them with instability frames for jumping attacks. \n- Increased recovery to rolling, movement and block on all jumping attacks. \n- Jump attacks no longer combo into R1s. \n- Adjusted sound effects for dashes. \n- Enabled dashes to be compatible with Carthus Milkring. \n- Reverted the projectile throw animation (firebombs, lightning urns, etc) to the Dark Souls 3 animation.\n- Removed all running attack to R1 true combos. \n- Adjusted recovery to roll on all rolling attacks to match their Dark Souls 3 counterparts: \n          - 1h Dagger = 6 frames\n          - Fists = 8 frames\n          - 1h Curved Sword = 7 frames  \n          - 1h Straight Sword = 9 frames \n          - 1h Axe = 12 frames \n          - 2h Halberd = 12 frames \n          - 2h Great Hammer = 17 frames \n          - 2h Ultra Greatsword = 18 frames \n\nStake Driver\n- Increased hitboxes on all attacks. \n- Increased active frames on transformed R2. \n- Rolling transformed R2 now reverts to untransformed after use. \n- Increased Strength and Dexterity scaling AR bonuses. \n- Reduced hitstun on second R1s to dagger stun, preventing them from comboing into the third R1. \n- Adjusted visuals, sound and damage registration on backstabs. \n- Adjusted visual and sound effects on transformed charged R2s and transformation. \n- Increased recovery to roll on untransformed second R2. \n- Removed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n- Removed ability of WA to feint into itself. \n\nSaw Cleaver\n- Increased tracking on transformed moveset.\n- Added a feint to R1 from the transformed running R1. \n- Increased motion values of transformed attacks. \n- Extended hitbox to the hilt on transformed R2. \n- Removed untransformed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n\nKirkhammer\n- Increased tracking on transformed R1s and L1s.\n- Increased Strength scaling AR bonuses. \n- Adjusted sound and visual effects on transformed attacks.\n- Added a feint to R1 to the transformed running R1. \n- Enabled TL1 to true combo into the followup transformed L1. \n- Transformed moveset is no longer parriable. \n- Reduced hitstun on the untransformed second and fourth R1 to dagger stun, preventing it from comboing into the followup R1. \n- Increased recovery to R2 on untransformed R1, preventing R1 to Jump Attack from being a true combo. \n- Reduced number of hyperarmor frames on transformation attacks. \n- Removed damage reduction from transformation attacks. \n- Reduced the delay before rocks begin to fall after using transformed WA. \n- Increased recovery to roll on untransformed second R2. \n- Removed untransformed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n- Made block frames on transformed kick start at frame 11. \n\nWhirligig Saw\n- Increased hyperarmor startup on transformed Stance WA to 16 frames. \n- Slightly improved tracking on transformed Stance WA. \n- Reduced motion value on transformed jumping attack. \n- Removed Dexterity scaling AR bonus and replaced with increased Strength scaling AR bonus. \n- Replaced the second transformed R2. \n- Increased tracking on transformed running R2. \n- Reduced poise health on transformed moveset to Glaive poise.\n- Increased tracking on transformed R1s to be on par with Glaive tracking. \n- Increased hitstun on untransformed WA, enabling it to be a true combo into WA R2. \n- Reduced hitstun on untransformed second R1 to dagger stun, preventing them from comboing into the third R1. \n- Increased motion value on untransformed R1s. \n- Removed untransformed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n\nLudwig’s Holy Blade\n- Reduced hitstun on the untransformed second and fourth R1 to dagger stun, preventing it from comboing into the followup R1. \n- Increased recovery to R2 on untransformed R1, preventing R1 to Jump Attack from being a true combo. \n- Removed untransformed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n- Removed damage reduction from transformation attacks. \n- Reduced number of hyperarmor frames on transformation attacks. \n- Increased tracking on transformed running R1 to be on par with Greatsword tracking. \n- Increased number of active frames on transformed first R2 by 4 frames. \n- Increased tracking on transformed second R2. \n- Decreased recovery on transformed R1s and L1s into attacks. \n- Increased recovery to roll on untransformed second R2. \n- WA now adds an extra 40 fire AR on top of its current effect of converting all AR into fire. \n- Transformed WA can now feint to R2 and L1. \n- Added a dagger stun shockwave to the transformed WA. \n- Tweaked sound and visual effects on transformed WA. \n- Transformed R2s and L1s are no longer parriable. \n- Made block frames on transformed kick start at frame 11. \n\nBlade of Mercy\n- Increased hitstun on transformed first R1 to straight sword stun, enabling it to true combo the first R1 into the second. \n- Increased hitboxes on R1 and L1 attacks. \n- Reduced hitstun on transformed rolling R1 to dagger stun. \n- Increased Dexterity and Intelligence scaling AR bonuses.\n- Changed transformed rolling L1 to Gotthard Twinswords rolling L1.\n- Changed transformed rolling R1 to Drang Twinspears rolling L1.  \n- Removed untransformed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n- Reduced hitstun on untransformed first R1 to dagger stun. \n\nHunter’s Axe\n- Increased Strength scaling AR bonuses. \n- Increased tracking on transformed R1s and L1s to be on par with Glaive tracking. \n- Added a feint to R1 on transformed WA. \n- Added a stamina cost to untransformed WA. \n- Increased motion value on first hit of transformed WA. \n- Adjusted visuals, sound and damage registration on backstabs. \n- Improved tracking on transformed rolling R1. \n- Removed untransformed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n\nRakuyo\n- Removed hyperarmor from transformed WA. \n- Increased recovery of R1s and L1s to WA on transformed moveset. \n- Reduced hitstun on consecutive R1s to prevent them comboing. \n- Increased motion value on untransformed R2. \n- Reduced hitbox on untransformed R2. \n- Removed R2 being able to feint to R2. \n- Slowed down recovery of transformed L1s to consecutive L1s by 4 frames. \n\nBug Fixes\n----------------\n- Fixed item descriptions on Bloodborne weapons being cut off. \n- Fixed dash/fast roll being able to escape hitstun. \n- Fixed Stake Driver not having a riposte animation. \n- Fixed Bloodborne kicks not doing stamina damage. \n- Fixed transformed 1h Bloodborne weapons untricking during riposte animations. \n- Fixed issues with Bloodborne weapons not disappearing during certain gestures. \n- Fixed numerous visual issues that occurred when performing certain actions with a transformed weapon. \n- Fixed untransformed Hunter’s Axe having the Glaive forward R2 instead of its intended jumping attack. \n- Fixed Handmaid&apos;s Dagger and Dagger having straight sword stun in the left hand. \n- Fixed Black Knight Glaive and Salvation Axes having the wrong moveset when used on female characters.</notes>
	</n12>
	<n11>
		<version>1.4.0</version>
		<notes>New Additions\n---------------------\n\nAdded eight new trick weapons: \n- Saw Cleaver\n- Ludwig’s Holy Blade\n- Whirligig Saw\n- Kirkhammer\n- Blades of Mercy \n- Rakuyo \n- Hunter Axe\n- Stake Driver \n\nChanged title screen image. \nUpdated music in certain areas: \n- Title Screen: Moonlit Melody \n- Character Creation: Maiden in Black\n- Firelink Shrine: Nameless Song\n- Firelink Shrine 2: Epilogue\n\n\nGeneral Changes \n--------------------------\n\nReworked starting classes to make other classes more efficient for certain builds:\n- Knight (SL9): \n12 Vig / 10 Att / 11 End / 15 Vit / 13 Str / 12 Dex / 9 Int / 9 Fth / 7 Lck\n- Mercenary (SL9) \n11 Vig / 11 / Att / 11 End / 10 Vit / 10 Str / 20 Dex / 10 Int / 8 Fth / 7 Lck\n- Warrior (SL9) \n14 Vig / 5 Att / 12 End / 11 Vit / 23 Str / 8 Dex / 8 Int / 9 Fth / 8 Lck\n- Herald (SL9) \n12 Vig / 11 Att / 9 End / 12 Vit / 12 Str / 11 Dex / 7 Int / 17 Fth / 7 Lck\n- Thief (SL9) \n10 Vig / 8 Att / 10 End / 9 Vit / 9 Str / 13 Dex / 8 Int / 8 Fth / 23 Lck \n- Assassin (SL9) \n10 Vig / 11 Att / 11 End / 10 Vit / 10 Str / 19 Dex / 13 Int / 7 Fth / 7 Lck\n- Sorcerer (SL9) \n9 Vig / 19 Att / 9 End / 7 Vit / 7 Str / 11 Dex / 23 Int / 6 Fth / 7 Lck\n- Pyromancer (SL9) \n11 Vig / 12 Att / 10 End / 8 Vit / 12 Str / 9 Dex / 14 Int / 14 Fth / 7 Lck\n- Cleric (SL9) \n10 Vig / 19 Att / 9 End / 7 Vit / 12 Str / 7 Dex / 6 Int / 21 Fth / 7 Lck\n- Deprived (SL1) \n8 Vig / 10 Att / 10 End / 8 Vit / 12 Str / 14 Dex / 10 Int / 10 Fth / 8 Lck\n\n- Changed rolling animation when under 30% equip load to the Bloodborne dash animation when locked on, and the Bloodborne rolling animation when unlocked. \n- Removed hyperarmor from Backsteps, and instead gave them iframes from frames 2 to 12. \n- Removed online censor for certain phrases in character names.  \n- Removed running R1 to R1 feint from Ultra Greatswords, Curved Greatswords, Greataxes and Greathammers.\n- Halved stamina consumption of all forms of Shieldpoke. \n- Increased motion value from 85 to 100 on all forms of Shieldpoke. \n- Forward R2s no longer combo to R1s. \n- Removed R1/R2 feints from all forms of Charge. \n- Returned hyperarmor startup on all forms of Charge to vanilla values. \n- Returned recovery to roll on all forms of Charge to vanilla values. \n- Increased hyperarmor startup of Galvanise to 11 frames. \n\nGreatshields\n- Reduced hitstun on second R1, preventing it from being a true combo into the third R1. \n- Removed damage reduction from all Shield Bashes. \n- Reduced block frames on all Shield Bashes. \n- Increased FP cost on all Shield Bashes. \n- Reduced hitboxes on all Shield Bashes. \n- Reduced active frames on Dragonslayer Greatshield variant of Shield Bash. \n- Reduced hyperarmor frames on R1, forward R2 and all Shield Bashes. \n- Removed L1 feint from Giant Door Shield running L1. \n\nUltra Greatswords\n- Increased hyperarmor startup of Legion Stomp to 11 frames. \n- Reduced motion value of Legion Stomp R2. \n- Reduced active frames on 2h forward R2. \n- Smoothened the startup animation for Farron Greatsword first 2h R1. \n\nStraight Swords\n- Valorheart block frames start 6 frames later on 2h R1. \n- Added damage reduction during the first 6 frames of startup on Valorheart 2h R1. \n- Increased recovery to R1/R2 for Silver Knight Straight Sword 1h R2. \n\nCurved Swords\n- Returned dagger hitstun to 2h second R1 (fast variant). \n\nKatanas\n- Reduced hitstun on Frayed Blade second WA R2, preventing it from comboing into a followup WA. \n\nAxes\n- Increased hyperarmor startup of Warcry to 11 frames. \n\nFists \n- Increased recovery to roll on Caestus WA. \n\nThrusting Swords\n- Decreased recovery of Crow Quills rolling L1 into follow up attacks. \n- Increased tracking of Crow Quills rolling L1. \n- Made Crow Quills rolling L1 start up slightly faster. \n\nGreathammers\n- Improved Molten Perseverance by making lava spawn on the first slam. \n- Increased speed of Ledo’s Greathammer 2h forward R2 by 25%. \n- Slightly reduced active frames on 2h forward R2. \n- Made hitbox on 1h R1 start 2 frames later. \n- Increased recovery of 1h R1 to R1. \n- Reduced number of hyperarmor frames on 1h R1.\n- Reduced tracking on Executioner’s Charge. \n- Removed hitstun from Kindled Flurry. \n- Greatly reduced frostbite buildup on Vordt’s Great Hammer variant of Champion’s Charge. \n- Increased gap between hyperarmor frames and roll for Pickaxe 2h R1, running R1 and forward R2. \n\nSpears and Pikes\n- Increased speed of buffed Ringed Knight Spear forward R2s by 25%. \n- Reduced tracking on Drang Twinspears 2h rolling L1. \n- Reducing tracking on Drang Twinspears Charge. \n- Increased stamina cost of Pike class running R1s. \n\nReapers\n- Increased speed of Friede’s Great Scythe 2h R1 by 20%. \n\nGreataxes \n- Increased speed of Demonic Flare by 40%. \n\nConsumables\n- Firebombs, Black Firebombs and Lightning Urns now use the throwing animation from Bloodborne. \n\nPyromancy \n- Increased recovery for Boulder Heave by 3 frames. \n- Increased Boulder Heave FP cost to 35.\n\n\nBug Fixes: \n-----------------\n\n- Fixed Sacred Chime of Filianore having staff R2s. \n- Fixed Pierce Shield Bash not having a hitbox. \n- Fixed Katana running R1s accidentally having less recovery than they did in vanilla. \n- Fixed bug with Exile Greatsword and Great Machete performing the wrong WA when used without the required FP. \n- Fixed animation bug with 1h Broadsword R2. \n- Fixed infinite feint bug with 1h Moonlight Greatsword R2s.</notes>
	</n11>
	<n10>
		<version>1.3.5</version>
		<notes>Great Hammers\n- Adjusted damage of Executioner’s Charge WA. \n- Adjusted damage of Smough’s Great Hammer first charged R2. \n- Smough’s Great Hammer no longer deals double damage with R2s vs bosses.\n- Executioner’s Charge WA final hit and charged first R2s have 100 lifesteal.\n\nShields\n- Added visual and auditory feedback for perfect blocks.</notes>
	</n10>
	<n9>
		<version>1.3.4</version>
		<notes>Changes\n-------------------\n\n- Enabled voice chat for every phantom\n- Executioner’s Charge now provides a lighting buff on smough’s greathammer.\n\n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed missing file left out of the previous patch by accident.\n- Fixed millwood axe WA allowing 2 hits after the last hit.\n- Executioner’s charge now true combos into the extension.</notes>
	</n9>
	<n8>
		<version>1.3.3</version>
		<notes>Balance Changes\n-------------------------\n\nStraight Swords\n- Slightly reduced physical scaling on Shortsword.\n\nReapers \n- Added damage reduction to Neck Swipe WA during hyperarmor frames. \n\nGreathammers\n- Replaced Galvanise WA on Smough’s Greathammer with new WA - “Executioner’s Charge”.\n\nStaves/Catalysts\n- Added a new third 1h R2 for Staves. \n\nRings \n- Flynn&apos;s Ring now has: \n      - Reduced weight. \n      - Increased status effect bonuses. \n      - Increased physical damage bonuses. \n\nSpells\n- Reduced hitstun on Black Serpent to Dagger Stun. \n- Increased Faith requirement for Blessed Weapon miracle from 15 to 20. \n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed bug for perfect block mechanic that didn’t allow you to perfect block when one-handing certain weapons with shields. \n- Fixed bug that allowed Gold and Silver Tracers WA to infinite combo. \n- Fixed bug with Eleonora where it had Sever WA instead of Spin Slash WA. \n- Fixed bug with Old King’s Greathammer where it still applied Perseverance WA when not meeting requirements. \n- Fixed bug with Dragon Bone Smasher where it had Greatsword moveset when equipped in the left hand. \n- Fixed bug that allowed two handed straight swords to feint forever with R2’s</notes>
	</n8>
	<n7>
		<version>1.3.2</version>
		<notes>Balance Changes\n-------------------------\n\nNew Perfect Block Mechanic for Shields\n- Perfect block occurs if you perform a frame-perfect block, which lasts for 1 frame (0.015s duration window).\n- Perfect blocks will cut damage after shield absorption by 70% and increase stability by 20%.\n\nShield Throw\n- Now deals strike damage instead of thrust.\n- Reduced tracking and removed block frames on throw.\n- Increased recovery to R1 and roll.\n- Reduced hitbox size and hitstun.\n\nCurved Swords\n- Increased the motion value on Pontiff Knight Curved Sword WA from 80 - 100 to 100 - 120, respectively for each hit.\n\nStraight Swords\n- Increased the speed and duration of Valorheart’s first R1 block frames.\n\nPikes\n- Increased the motion value on the last hit of Greatlance’s jumping attack from 75 to 100.\n\nHammers &amp; Greathammers\n- Pickaxe 2h R1 combo is now more consistent.\n- Ledo’s Greathammer while buffed can now cancel from running R1 into R1/R2.\n\nGreatswords\n- Reduced the motion value on all Greatsword’s 1h jump attacks from 118 to 90.\n- Reduced the motion value on all Greatsword’s 2h jump attacks from 125 to 100.\n\nUltra Greatswords\n- Removed the R2 into WA feint for Zweihander, Profaned Greatsword (only charged), Farron Greatsword, Cathedral Knight Greatsword, Greatsword, Black Knight Greatsword, Lothric Knight Greatsword, and Ringed Knight Paired Greatswords.\n- Reduced the motion value on Dragon Bone Smasher’s 1h jump attack from 118 to 90.\n- Reduced the motion value on Dragon Bone Smasher’s 2h jump attack from 125 to 100.\n\nBows\n- Quickstep L1 cancel recovery increased.\n- Black Bow of Pharis has 3 arrows now instead of 4.\n\nWhips\nRose of Ariandel can now perform a jump attack while 2h.\n\nSpells\n- All weapon spell buffs stamina cost reduced from 200 to 100 stamina.\n- Blessed Weapon no longer regenerates, but will heal the user after consecutive hits for 40 hp per proc.\n- Gentle Prayer now costs 200 stamina.\n- Way of White Corona stops tracking once fired.\n\nItems\n- Kukri stops tracking once the projectile is thrown.\n- Kukri throw into roll recovery is 5 frames faster.\n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed Pontiff Knight Curved Sword 2h R1 not having stun.\n- Rotten Ghru Dagger has Chain Dance WA and can backstab again.\n- Pontiff Knight Great Scythe WA R2 will no longer combo into R1 or R2.\n- Fixed a bug where players couldn’t perform jump attacks with an offhand talisman.\n- Fixed offhand 2h R2 while talisman is in the mainhand.\n- Fixed vanilla bug where fire- and chaos storm spawned under the floor at old wolf.</notes>
	</n7>
	<n6>
		<version>1.3.1</version>
		<notes>Balance Changes\n-------------------------\n\n- Dragon Bone Smasher weight reduced from 30 to 28.\n- Added a 2nd 1h R2 for Greatshields and added a feint for Giant Door Shields.\n- Changed FP cost for Unfaltering Prayer.\n- Unfaltering Prayer on light talismans (ie. Saint’s Talisman) now cost 8 FP.\n- Unfaltering Prayer on medium talismans (ie. Canvas Talisman) now cost 4 FP.\n- Unfaltering Prayer on strong talismans (ie. Sunlight Talisman) now cost 0 FP.\n- Carthus Bloodring now adds 3 i-frames to fat rolls only.\n- Rapier Parry now has vanilla animation and frame data.\n- 6f startup (4f active)\n- 25f roll cancel\n- Changed stun on Irithyll Rapier WA from Ultra stun to Straight Sword stun.\n- Dragon Head Stone allows you to sprint while using it.\n- Dragon Head Stone fire doesn’t stun anymore.\n- Twinkling Dragon Head Stone has increased range on its fire breath.\n- Shield Throw stamina cost reduced to 24 + 26 from 24 + 56.\n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed some frostbite procs not having the new improved effect.\n- Fixed Lothric’s Great Scythe not having a hitbox for its second R2s.\n- Fixed frost effect on Irithyll Straight Sword/Rapier and Pontiff Knight Curved Sword WA not showing the outer rim of frost icicles.\n- Fixed Pontiff Knight Curved Sword WA while in the offhand.\n- Pontiff Knight Curved Sword and Irithyll Straight Sword WA no longer allow for 3 hit combos, have reduced frost buildup, and do not have an extended hitbox while out of FP.\n- Fixed Thrusting Sword shieldpokes.\n- Fixed Greathammer bug where 2nd R2 could be block cancelled on startup.\n- Fixed Executioner’s Greatsword WA R2 hitbox.\n- Way of White Corona now returns all 5 disks.</notes>
	</n6>
	<n5>
		<version>1.3</version>
		<notes>New Additions\n---------------------\n\n- Added a new Ultra Greatsword: Dragon Bone Smasher.\n- Added a new blue Sherbet.\n\n\nGeneral Changes\n-------------------------\n\nBalance Changes\n- Fat rolls create a shockwave with knockback and dagger stun as you land. \n- Improved poise health and all cancel windows (except roll) of fat rolls.\n\n- Increased physical scaling on weapons infused with Blessed with emphasis on Strength scaling. \n- Increased physical scaling on weapons infused with Simple with emphasis on Dexterity scaling.\n\n- Decreased startup of kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas from 4 frames to 3 frames. \n- Decreased stamina cost of kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas from 30 stamina to 20 stamina. \n- Increased hitbox size for kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas. \n- Decreased distance in which opponents are knocked back by kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas. \n\nArmor\n- Kicks deal bonus damage if they are performed with pieces of the Armor of Thorns set. \n- Shira’s Crown boosts lightning damage by 10%, but reduces lightning absorption by 30%. \n- Pyromancer’s Crown boosts fire damage by 10%, but reduces fire absorption by 30%. \n\nDragon Form Overhaul\n- Buffed absorption and poise of Dragon Form. \n\n- Dragon Head Stone attack startup decreased from 37 frames to 14 frames. \n- Dragon Head Stone attack is now rollable upon releasing it. \n- Decreased recovery for Dragon Head Stone attack. \n\n- Twinkling Dragon Head Stone attack startup decreased from 74 frames to 39 frames. \n- Twinkling Dragon Head Stone attack is now rollable from startup and recovery. \n- Recovery decreased on Twinkling Dragon Head Stone attack. \n\n- Decreased startup on Dragon Torso Stone roar from 14 frames to 11 frames. \n- Dragon Torso Stone roar now hits three times. \n- Dragon Torso Stone roar now applies a stamina regen buff of 50% to the user. \n- Recovery decreased for Dragon Torso Stone roar. \n\n- Decreased recovery on Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack from 56 frames to 39 frames. \n- Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack can now be rolled on startup. \n- Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack hits twice. \n- Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack applies a stamina regen buff of 50% to the user. \n- Decreased recovery on Twinkling Dragon Torso stone attack.\n- Added poise health to Twinkling Dragon Torso stone attack (40 Poise Health at 80%).\n\nShields\n- New Forward R2 for 2h Shields. \n- Tracking on Shield 2h R1s reverted to vanilla. \n- Lowered stamina consumption for all Greatshield attacks by 0.75x. \n\n- Returned WA of Havel’s Greatshield to Stoneflesh. \n- Silver Knight Shield now has Weapon Skill instead of Parry. \n- Changed the health regen of Ancient Dragon Greatshield from 2 HP every second to 3 HP every 2 seconds. \n\n- Increased stability of Bonewheel Shield from 59 to 62. \n- Decreased weight of Bonewheel Shield from 15 to 12. \n- Decreased stamina consumption of Bonewheel Shield WA from 40 stamina to 20 stamina. \n- Bonewheel Shield WA now hits four times instead of three. \n- Startup of Bonewheel Shield WA decreased from 29 frames to 27. \n- Decreased hyperarmor startup of Bonewheel Shield WA from frame 29 to frame 13. \n- FP is now consumed on frame 20 instead of frame 27 on Bonewheel Shield WA. \n- Recovery on Bonewheel Shield WA decreased by four frames. \n\n- Sunset Shield, Spiked Shield and Sunlight Shield now have a new “Shield Throw” WA. The user throws a spectral disc, reminiscent of the Crystal Ring Shield special attack in Dark Souls 1. \n\n- Increased stamina regen bonus from Grass Crest Shield from 4 to 10 stamina per second. \n- Increased physical absorption on Grass Crest Shield from 89 to 100. \nDecreased stability on Grass Crest Shield to 54 from 57. \n\nAxes &amp; Greataxes\n- Removed R2 feint on release version of Warcry R2s. \n- Changed motion value of Butcher Knife WA R2. \n- Butcher Knife WA R2 now deals Standard damage. \n- Increased AR of Thrall Axe. \n- Returned moveset and WA of Great Machete to the moveset it had in Ashes 1.0. \n- Increased R2 feint window on charged version of Warcry R2s for Axes and Crescent Axe. \n\nCurved Swords &amp; Great Curved Swords\n- Increased recovery to R1 from Running R1 on 2h fast Curved Swords. \n- Decreased tracking on 2h R1s for fast Curved Swords. \n\n- Increased tracking for Frost Blade WA. \n- Decreased recovery for Frost Blade WA. \n- Added ice wave effect from Friede’s Great Scythe WA R2 to Frost Blade WA.\n- Decreased 2h R1 speed of Pontiff Knight Curved Sword. \n- Added innate Frost build- up to Pontiff Knight Curved Sword. \n\n- Returned moveset and WA of all Curved Greatswords to the moveset they had in Ashes 1.0.\n\nDaggers\n- Returned kick attack for Daggers to the kick attack they had in Ashes 1.0. \n- Added R2 feint to the Tailbone Shortsword WA.\n- Removed WA feint from Mailbreaker second 1h R2. \n- Added WA feint to Mailbreaker first 2h R2. \n\nFists &amp; Claws\n- Changed Strength scaling of Bare Fists.\n- Offhand Demon Fist and offhand Crow Talons now have Weapon Skill instead of Parry. \n\nGreatswords\n- Drakeblood Greatsword now has Hammer poise health on 2h R1s. \n- Drakeblood Greatsword now displays blue lightning when hitting an opponent, rather than yellow lightning. \n- Hyperarmor startup of second and third Drakeblood Greatsword 2h R1s is now slower. \n- Removed first 2h R1 to WA true combo on Drakeblood Greatsword. \n- Improved recovery of 1h Drakeblood Greatsword R2 to R1. \n- Drakeblood Greatsword can now true combo the second and third 2h R1s to WA. \n\n- Fixed Moonlight Greatsword stamina consumption and hitboxes. \n\nUltra Greatswords \n- Removed the second R1 to R2 true combo for Ultra Greatswords. \n- Removed the ability for Ultra Greatswords to feint R2 into Stomp. \n- Made 2h R1 to Forward R2 a reliable true combo for Ultra Greatswords. \n- Adjusted Cathedral Knight Greatsword stomp R2 stamina consumption to be the same as the Greatsword stomp R2.\n- Removed damage reduction from Stomp WA on Fume Ultra Greatsword. \n\nHalberds &amp; Glaives\n- Removed the ability for Spin Sweep to skip to the WA extension. \n- Red Hilted Halberd WA R1 stamina consumption increased from 20 to 60\n- Red Hilted Halberd WA stance cancel to R1 / R2 increased from 0 frames to 5 frames. \n- Red Hilted Halberd WA R2 shockwave no longer true combos into WA R1. \n\n- Increased range of Winged Knight Halberd attacks to be more accurate to the visual model. \n- Increased AR of Winged Knight Halberd. \n- Fixed polyIDs on 1h Forward R2 for Lucerne, Glaive, Splitleaf, Black Knight Glaive and Crucifix of the Mad King. \n\nCrossbows \n- Repeating Crossbow WA fires 20 bolts instead of 10. \n- Stamina consumption of Repeating Crossbow WA doubled. \n\n- Crossbow Tackle WA now hits 5 times, increased from 3. \n- Crossbow Tackle WA startup decreased from 26 frames to 17 frames. \n- Crossbow Tackle WA recovery decreased by 5 frames. \n\nHammers &amp; Greathammers\n- Removed the ability for Spin Bash to skip to the WA extension.\n- Decreased startup on 1h Greathammer and 1h Pickaxe R1s from 24 frames to 20 frames. \n- Decreased recovery on 1h Greathammer and 1h Pickaxe R1s by 5 frames. \n- Changed the 1h Greathammer second R1 to the 1h Pickaxe second R1. \n- Decreased recovery on Pickaxe 2h R1 by 4 frames. \n- Offhand first R1 for Greathammers and Pickaxe has the same frame data as the mainhand first R1. \n\n- Quakestone Hammer can now be buffed.\n- Reduced scaling on Mace when infused with Blessed. \n- Changed the Rolling R1 for Ledo’s Greathammer when buffed with WA to match that of other Greathammers. \n\nKatanas\n- Increased Strength scaling on Black Blade. \n- Lowered Dexterity requirement on Black Blade to 16. \n- Increased recovery to Forward R2 from Running R1 on 2h Katanas.\n\nScythes\n- 2h Lothric Scythe and Pontiff Knight Great Scythe both have the Curved Greatsword/Reaper kick attack.\n- Increased R1/R2 buffer window for Neck Swipe WA. \n\nSpears &amp; Pikes\n- Spears shieldpoke is now as fast as Thrusting Sword shieldpoke. \n- Removed the ability for Pikes to feint the Running R1. \n\nStraight Swords\n- Made the transition from 1h and 2h charged R2s with Dark Sword to uncharged R2s faster by 3 frames. \n- Reduced motion value of Straight Sword stance WA R2 to vanilla. \n- Returned original moveset to Irithyll Straight Sword.\n- Altered moveset of Silver Knight Straight Sword. \n- Shortsword, Broadsword and Broken Straight Sword have unique, faster 2h R1s. \n- Reduced AR of Shortsword and Broadsword.\n- Improved tracking of 2h Valorheart Forward R2. \n- Changed the health regen of Anri’s Straight Sword from 2 HP every 2 seconds to 2 HP every 4 seconds. \n- Removed the ability for Lothric Knight Sword to feint R2 into Stance. \n\nThrusting Swords \n- Irithyll Rapier has a new weapon art. \n\nWhips\n- Witch&apos;s Locks can now perform backstabs and ripostes. \n\nSpells\n- Black Serpent can no longer feint. \n- Black Serpent recovery increased by 5 frames.\n\n- Lifehunt Scythe can be turned while casting.\n\n- Way of White Corona now fires 5 projectiles in front.\n- Increased motion value of Way of White Corona projectiles from 85 to 100.\n- Increased stamina damage of Way of White Corona projectiles from 30 stamina to 60 stamina.\n- Increased the duration for which thrown Way of White Corona projectiles linger before returning to the caster. \n\n- Healing spells have an additional effect. Regain HP through consecutive attacks. This effect has a duration of 20 seconds. \n\nCatalysts &amp; Staves\n- Staves can now perform Forward R2s. \n- Staves now have new R2 chains. \n- Murky Longstaff has special effects during swing animations. \n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Sacred Bloom Shield no longer has a bug causing it to perform the Silver Knight Straight Sword WA. \n- Fixed Thrusting Sword parry animation. \n- Fixed a bug where charged 2h Curved Sword R2s had the Moonlight Greatsword sound effect. \n- Fixed clipping issue with Footman’s Hood. \n- Fixed animation issue with Lothric Scythe caused by not meeting the requirements. \n- Fixed a bug with Greatshield hitboxes. \n- Resolved a bug where offhand hybrid catalysts would trigger mainhand catalyst spells when pressing L2. \n- Using Siegbrau no longer consumes stamina.</notes>
	</n5>
	<n4>
		<version>1.2.1</version>
		<notes>- Added simplified Chinese in-game item descriptions (thanks Nep.Bin)</notes>
	</n4>
	<n3>
		<version>1.2</version>
		<notes>- Estus and Ashen stamina cost reverted back to normal\n- offhand rotten ghru doesn't block anymore\n- offhand murkey doesn't use shield attacks \n- Fixed parrying dagger offhand\n- Fixed crossbow reload back to vanilla \n- Irithyll SS and SKSS don't have poise for 2h \n- Fixed issue where you can recovery cancel offhand attacks \n- Fixed issue where certain stance attacks don't come out fast enough \n- Fixed quickstep glitch and now it stuns properly \n- Changed harald/mechete firt r1s \n- Nerfed shields damage and block frames\n- Fixed parry frames for crow quills \n- bows that had puncture as weapon art now use puncture all the time as normal arrow \n- composite/short bows have faster r1 to r1 bow \n- pharis is able to fire 3 arrows from normal r1s/r2s \n- ledos when buffed now can feint</notes>
	</n3>
	<n2>
		<version>1.1</version>
		<notes>New changes\n----------------\n\n- Complete overhaul with offhand mechanic\n   - All weapons have L1 as the chain combo \n   - All weapons allow weapon skill similar to shields except:\n      - Crystal sage/rapier: these have an offhand running attack for L2\n      - Crow quills: L2 uses new improved parry \n      - Scimitar, ghru, pkcs: These have an offhand running attack for l2 \n      - Painted guardian: kept the parry for l2 \n      - Claws/fist: still parry \n- As a result of previous change, Barefists were reverted back to vanilla AR and scaling \n- Thrusting Halberds gained Shieldpoke \n- Estus now takes you to negative stamina and caps at negative 60. You can still chug multiple estus regardless of stamina\n- Ashen estus cost 30 stamina \n- Gave silver knight SS new R1s matching its Dks1 counterpart while also having better synergy to WA than normal ss r1s and able to panic roll catch on 3rd r1\n- New moveset for broadsword and improved its HA to Hammer level when 2h \n- Dragonslayer Axe Gained lightning strike WA\n- Drakeblood GS Gained Lightning strike WA\n- Silver knight spear WA r1 reduced stamina consumption by half \n- Harald CGS gained a new moveset\n- Great Machete Gained a new moveset \n- Butcher’s knife gained a new weapon art executioner's stomp \n- Irithyll SS gained a new moveset and a new spin slash that shoots Ice at the end of it\n- Lorian GS gained Dimension Strike WA and increased its innate fire slightly for losing buff \n- Lothric scythe got much more fitting overall moveset\n- Lothric scythe Gained R2 feint as well on WA and improved its feint window\n- Replaced 3 gestures into dark souls 1 gestures\n   - Point down to “Triple point down” \n   - Welcome to “well what is it” \n   - Point up to “Look skyward” \n- Kick buffer window made 10frames before active frame \n- All forms of stances (hold, rapier stance etc) weapon arts got reduction to FP cost \n- Stance WA r2 for GS and SS got improved MV \n- Pontiff Scythe gained a new kick when two handed\n- Removed poise from SKSS WA \n- Nerfed poise start up, fp consumption, and wa to wa cancel of caestus WA\n- Replaced Vordt WA to Champion’s Charge\n- Nerfed WA to WA and tracking of immolation tinder Weapon art \n- Crossbow reload is now back to vanilla \n- Adjusted tracking on r1s of Vertical UGS, GA, and Scythes to have better tracking than vanilla if unlocked but now are straffable if they attack lock on \n- Nerfed Wolf GS wa r2 tracking \n- Nerfed Black knight GS wa tracking\n- Improved Follower Javalin’s HA \n- Havel shield gained shield bash\n- Bowglitch fixed both mainhand and offhand by change all weapon art into quickstep \n- Bows can be equipped offhand now\n- Improved Bows overall recovery significantly \n- Only bows have quickstep and it function different than vanilla where it has no iframe but it has HA, damage reduction, and a stagger stun if bump into people with quickstep \n- Rapier wa r1 feint cost stamina and its MV decreased to normal r1 level\n- Rapier wa r2 motion value increased  \n- Added R1/r2 feints sword of judgment WA R2\n- Decreased Gotthard and onkiri 2h r1s tracking\n- Improved poise level for 2h forward r2 of scythes and halberd \n- Improved follower WA tracking slighly and gave it its extension R1/r2 cancels \n- Black knight GA gained a new kick when two handed\n- Gave all form of spin slashes ability to skip to 2nd r1 using wa to r1 cancel from 0 to 5 frames window \n- Improved Astora’s base AR slightly and removed its 12 faith requirement \n- Made Shield 2h r1s chain better due to better range \n- Greatshields gained new jumping attacks\n- Improved 2h thrusting halberd speed\n- Improved offhand synergy with main hand on utilities that allow weapon skill\n\n\nFixed bugs\n-------------\n\n- Fixed Lothric scythe not being able to backstab\n- Fixed irithyll SS not being able to backstab\n- Fixed Harald CGS not being able to backstab\n- Fixed makoto parry animation when 1h \n- Fixed PKCS no FP issue\n- Fixed Millwood wa to r1 not comboing properly \n- Fixed issue where 1h forward r2 does not have hitbox for frayed blade\n- Harpe and crescent CS only get buff outside of the feint window\n- Removed dagger infinite \n- Fixed 2h running dagger roll cancel\n- Fixed caestus bullet’s lightning effect\n- Fixed Salvation axes sorting sorting issue in the menu\n- Slowed fire whip down a little to fix huge damage true combos\n- Souls stream’s infinite issue \n- Fixed issue where yorshka/crystal chime didnt have stamina cost\n- Fixed issue where heavy cs had ss stun on 2h backswings \n- Fixed issue where offhand sorcery casting didn't feint \n- Fixed red hilted T-pose issue\n- Fixed immolation tinder farron flash sword no hitstun issue \n- Fixed issue where great chaos cost more stamina than vanilla \n- Fixed issue where fume and other ugs do the wrong push for 2h full charge r2s \n- Fixed no fp lothric doing wrong throw/push instead of pancake\n- Fixed greatshield shieldbash to now use stamina when feint instead of fp</notes>
	</n2>
	<n1>
		<version>1.0</version>
		<notes>First public release on nexusmods.</notes>
	</n1>
</UpdateNotes>
