<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<UpdateNotes>
	<n10>
		<version>1.3.5</version>
		<notes>Great Hammers\n- Adjusted damage of Executioner’s Charge WA. \n- Adjusted damage of Smough’s Great Hammer first charged R2. \n- Smough’s Great Hammer no longer deals double damage with R2s vs bosses.\n- Executioner’s Charge WA final hit and charged first R2s have 100 lifesteal.\n\nShields\n- Added visual and auditory feedback for perfect blocks.</notes>
	</n10>
	<n9>
		<version>1.3.4</version>
		<notes>Changes\n-------------------\n\n- Enabled voice chat for every phantom\n- Executioner’s Charge now provides a lighting buff on smough’s greathammer.\n\n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed missing file left out of the previous patch by accident.\n- Fixed millwood axe WA allowing 2 hits after the last hit.\n- Executioner’s charge now true combos into the extension.</notes>
	</n9>
	<n8>
		<version>1.3.3</version>
		<notes>Balance Changes\n-------------------------\n\nStraight Swords\n- Slightly reduced physical scaling on Shortsword.\n\nReapers \n- Added damage reduction to Neck Swipe WA during hyperarmor frames. \n\nGreathammers\n- Replaced Galvanise WA on Smough’s Greathammer with new WA - “Executioner’s Charge”.\n\nStaves/Catalysts\n- Added a new third 1h R2 for Staves. \n\nRings \n- Flynn&apos;s Ring now has: \n      - Reduced weight. \n      - Increased status effect bonuses. \n      - Increased physical damage bonuses. \n\nSpells\n- Reduced hitstun on Black Serpent to Dagger Stun. \n- Increased Faith requirement for Blessed Weapon miracle from 15 to 20. \n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed bug for perfect block mechanic that didn’t allow you to perfect block when one-handing certain weapons with shields. \n- Fixed bug that allowed Gold and Silver Tracers WA to infinite combo. \n- Fixed bug with Eleonora where it had Sever WA instead of Spin Slash WA. \n- Fixed bug with Old King’s Greathammer where it still applied Perseverance WA when not meeting requirements. \n- Fixed bug with Dragon Bone Smasher where it had Greatsword moveset when equipped in the left hand. \n- Fixed bug that allowed two handed straight swords to feint forever with R2’s</notes>
	</n8>
	<n7>
		<version>1.3.2</version>
		<notes>Balance Changes\n-------------------------\n\nNew Perfect Block Mechanic for Shields\n- Perfect block occurs if you perform a frame-perfect block, which lasts for 1 frame (0.015s duration window).\n- Perfect blocks will cut damage after shield absorption by 70% and increase stability by 20%.\n\nShield Throw\n- Now deals strike damage instead of thrust.\n- Reduced tracking and removed block frames on throw.\n- Increased recovery to R1 and roll.\n- Reduced hitbox size and hitstun.\n\nCurved Swords\n- Increased the motion value on Pontiff Knight Curved Sword WA from 80 - 100 to 100 - 120, respectively for each hit.\n\nStraight Swords\n- Increased the speed and duration of Valorheart’s first R1 block frames.\n\nPikes\n- Increased the motion value on the last hit of Greatlance’s jumping attack from 75 to 100.\n\nHammers &amp; Greathammers\n- Pickaxe 2h R1 combo is now more consistent.\n- Ledo’s Greathammer while buffed can now cancel from running R1 into R1/R2.\n\nGreatswords\n- Reduced the motion value on all Greatsword’s 1h jump attacks from 118 to 90.\n- Reduced the motion value on all Greatsword’s 2h jump attacks from 125 to 100.\n\nUltra Greatswords\n- Removed the R2 into WA feint for Zweihander, Profaned Greatsword (only charged), Farron Greatsword, Cathedral Knight Greatsword, Greatsword, Black Knight Greatsword, Lothric Knight Greatsword, and Ringed Knight Paired Greatswords.\n- Reduced the motion value on Dragon Bone Smasher’s 1h jump attack from 118 to 90.\n- Reduced the motion value on Dragon Bone Smasher’s 2h jump attack from 125 to 100.\n\nBows\n- Quickstep L1 cancel recovery increased.\n- Black Bow of Pharis has 3 arrows now instead of 4.\n\nWhips\nRose of Ariandel can now perform a jump attack while 2h.\n\nSpells\n- All weapon spell buffs stamina cost reduced from 200 to 100 stamina.\n- Blessed Weapon no longer regenerates, but will heal the user after consecutive hits for 40 hp per proc.\n- Gentle Prayer now costs 200 stamina.\n- Way of White Corona stops tracking once fired.\n\nItems\n- Kukri stops tracking once the projectile is thrown.\n- Kukri throw into roll recovery is 5 frames faster.\n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed Pontiff Knight Curved Sword 2h R1 not having stun.\n- Rotten Ghru Dagger has Chain Dance WA and can backstab again.\n- Pontiff Knight Great Scythe WA R2 will no longer combo into R1 or R2.\n- Fixed a bug where players couldn’t perform jump attacks with an offhand talisman.\n- Fixed offhand 2h R2 while talisman is in the mainhand.\n- Fixed vanilla bug where fire- and chaos storm spawned under the floor at old wolf.</notes>
	</n7>
	<n6>
		<version>1.3.1</version>
		<notes>Balance Changes\n-------------------------\n\n- Dragon Bone Smasher weight reduced from 30 to 28.\n- Added a 2nd 1h R2 for Greatshields and added a feint for Giant Door Shields.\n- Changed FP cost for Unfaltering Prayer.\n- Unfaltering Prayer on light talismans (ie. Saint’s Talisman) now cost 8 FP.\n- Unfaltering Prayer on medium talismans (ie. Canvas Talisman) now cost 4 FP.\n- Unfaltering Prayer on strong talismans (ie. Sunlight Talisman) now cost 0 FP.\n- Carthus Bloodring now adds 3 i-frames to fat rolls only.\n- Rapier Parry now has vanilla animation and frame data.\n- 6f startup (4f active)\n- 25f roll cancel\n- Changed stun on Irithyll Rapier WA from Ultra stun to Straight Sword stun.\n- Dragon Head Stone allows you to sprint while using it.\n- Dragon Head Stone fire doesn’t stun anymore.\n- Twinkling Dragon Head Stone has increased range on its fire breath.\n- Shield Throw stamina cost reduced to 24 + 26 from 24 + 56.\n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Fixed some frostbite procs not having the new improved effect.\n- Fixed Lothric’s Great Scythe not having a hitbox for its second R2s.\n- Fixed frost effect on Irithyll Straight Sword/Rapier and Pontiff Knight Curved Sword WA not showing the outer rim of frost icicles.\n- Fixed Pontiff Knight Curved Sword WA while in the offhand.\n- Pontiff Knight Curved Sword and Irithyll Straight Sword WA no longer allow for 3 hit combos, have reduced frost buildup, and do not have an extended hitbox while out of FP.\n- Fixed Thrusting Sword shieldpokes.\n- Fixed Greathammer bug where 2nd R2 could be block cancelled on startup.\n- Fixed Executioner’s Greatsword WA R2 hitbox.\n- Way of White Corona now returns all 5 disks.</notes>
	</n6>
	<n5>
		<version>1.3</version>
		<notes>New Additions\n---------------------\n\n- Added a new Ultra Greatsword: Dragon Bone Smasher.\n- Added a new blue Sherbet.\n\n\nGeneral Changes\n-------------------------\n\nBalance Changes\n- Fat rolls create a shockwave with knockback and dagger stun as you land. \n- Improved poise health and all cancel windows (except roll) of fat rolls.\n\n- Increased physical scaling on weapons infused with Blessed with emphasis on Strength scaling. \n- Increased physical scaling on weapons infused with Simple with emphasis on Dexterity scaling.\n\n- Decreased startup of kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas from 4 frames to 3 frames. \n- Decreased stamina cost of kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas from 30 stamina to 20 stamina. \n- Increased hitbox size for kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas. \n- Decreased distance in which opponents are knocked back by kick attack for Claws, Daggers and Katanas. \n\nArmor\n- Kicks deal bonus damage if they are performed with pieces of the Armor of Thorns set. \n- Shira’s Crown boosts lightning damage by 10%, but reduces lightning absorption by 30%. \n- Pyromancer’s Crown boosts fire damage by 10%, but reduces fire absorption by 30%. \n\nDragon Form Overhaul\n- Buffed absorption and poise of Dragon Form. \n\n- Dragon Head Stone attack startup decreased from 37 frames to 14 frames. \n- Dragon Head Stone attack is now rollable upon releasing it. \n- Decreased recovery for Dragon Head Stone attack. \n\n- Twinkling Dragon Head Stone attack startup decreased from 74 frames to 39 frames. \n- Twinkling Dragon Head Stone attack is now rollable from startup and recovery. \n- Recovery decreased on Twinkling Dragon Head Stone attack. \n\n- Decreased startup on Dragon Torso Stone roar from 14 frames to 11 frames. \n- Dragon Torso Stone roar now hits three times. \n- Dragon Torso Stone roar now applies a stamina regen buff of 50% to the user. \n- Recovery decreased for Dragon Torso Stone roar. \n\n- Decreased recovery on Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack from 56 frames to 39 frames. \n- Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack can now be rolled on startup. \n- Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack hits twice. \n- Twinkling Dragon Torso Stone attack applies a stamina regen buff of 50% to the user. \n- Decreased recovery on Twinkling Dragon Torso stone attack.\n- Added poise health to Twinkling Dragon Torso stone attack (40 Poise Health at 80%).\n\nShields\n- New Forward R2 for 2h Shields. \n- Tracking on Shield 2h R1s reverted to vanilla. \n- Lowered stamina consumption for all Greatshield attacks by 0.75x. \n\n- Returned WA of Havel’s Greatshield to Stoneflesh. \n- Silver Knight Shield now has Weapon Skill instead of Parry. \n- Changed the health regen of Ancient Dragon Greatshield from 2 HP every second to 3 HP every 2 seconds. \n\n- Increased stability of Bonewheel Shield from 59 to 62. \n- Decreased weight of Bonewheel Shield from 15 to 12. \n- Decreased stamina consumption of Bonewheel Shield WA from 40 stamina to 20 stamina. \n- Bonewheel Shield WA now hits four times instead of three. \n- Startup of Bonewheel Shield WA decreased from 29 frames to 27. \n- Decreased hyperarmor startup of Bonewheel Shield WA from frame 29 to frame 13. \n- FP is now consumed on frame 20 instead of frame 27 on Bonewheel Shield WA. \n- Recovery on Bonewheel Shield WA decreased by four frames. \n\n- Sunset Shield, Spiked Shield and Sunlight Shield now have a new “Shield Throw” WA. The user throws a spectral disc, reminiscent of the Crystal Ring Shield special attack in Dark Souls 1. \n\n- Increased stamina regen bonus from Grass Crest Shield from 4 to 10 stamina per second. \n- Increased physical absorption on Grass Crest Shield from 89 to 100. \nDecreased stability on Grass Crest Shield to 54 from 57. \n\nAxes &amp; Greataxes\n- Removed R2 feint on release version of Warcry R2s. \n- Changed motion value of Butcher Knife WA R2. \n- Butcher Knife WA R2 now deals Standard damage. \n- Increased AR of Thrall Axe. \n- Returned moveset and WA of Great Machete to the moveset it had in Ashes 1.0. \n- Increased R2 feint window on charged version of Warcry R2s for Axes and Crescent Axe. \n\nCurved Swords &amp; Great Curved Swords\n- Increased recovery to R1 from Running R1 on 2h fast Curved Swords. \n- Decreased tracking on 2h R1s for fast Curved Swords. \n\n- Increased tracking for Frost Blade WA. \n- Decreased recovery for Frost Blade WA. \n- Added ice wave effect from Friede’s Great Scythe WA R2 to Frost Blade WA.\n- Decreased 2h R1 speed of Pontiff Knight Curved Sword. \n- Added innate Frost build- up to Pontiff Knight Curved Sword. \n\n- Returned moveset and WA of all Curved Greatswords to the moveset they had in Ashes 1.0.\n\nDaggers\n- Returned kick attack for Daggers to the kick attack they had in Ashes 1.0. \n- Added R2 feint to the Tailbone Shortsword WA.\n- Removed WA feint from Mailbreaker second 1h R2. \n- Added WA feint to Mailbreaker first 2h R2. \n\nFists &amp; Claws\n- Changed Strength scaling of Bare Fists.\n- Offhand Demon Fist and offhand Crow Talons now have Weapon Skill instead of Parry. \n\nGreatswords\n- Drakeblood Greatsword now has Hammer poise health on 2h R1s. \n- Drakeblood Greatsword now displays blue lightning when hitting an opponent, rather than yellow lightning. \n- Hyperarmor startup of second and third Drakeblood Greatsword 2h R1s is now slower. \n- Removed first 2h R1 to WA true combo on Drakeblood Greatsword. \n- Improved recovery of 1h Drakeblood Greatsword R2 to R1. \n- Drakeblood Greatsword can now true combo the second and third 2h R1s to WA. \n\n- Fixed Moonlight Greatsword stamina consumption and hitboxes. \n\nUltra Greatswords \n- Removed the second R1 to R2 true combo for Ultra Greatswords. \n- Removed the ability for Ultra Greatswords to feint R2 into Stomp. \n- Made 2h R1 to Forward R2 a reliable true combo for Ultra Greatswords. \n- Adjusted Cathedral Knight Greatsword stomp R2 stamina consumption to be the same as the Greatsword stomp R2.\n- Removed damage reduction from Stomp WA on Fume Ultra Greatsword. \n\nHalberds &amp; Glaives\n- Removed the ability for Spin Sweep to skip to the WA extension. \n- Red Hilted Halberd WA R1 stamina consumption increased from 20 to 60\n- Red Hilted Halberd WA stance cancel to R1 / R2 increased from 0 frames to 5 frames. \n- Red Hilted Halberd WA R2 shockwave no longer true combos into WA R1. \n\n- Increased range of Winged Knight Halberd attacks to be more accurate to the visual model. \n- Increased AR of Winged Knight Halberd. \n- Fixed polyIDs on 1h Forward R2 for Lucerne, Glaive, Splitleaf, Black Knight Glaive and Crucifix of the Mad King. \n\nCrossbows \n- Repeating Crossbow WA fires 20 bolts instead of 10. \n- Stamina consumption of Repeating Crossbow WA doubled. \n\n- Crossbow Tackle WA now hits 5 times, increased from 3. \n- Crossbow Tackle WA startup decreased from 26 frames to 17 frames. \n- Crossbow Tackle WA recovery decreased by 5 frames. \n\nHammers &amp; Greathammers\n- Removed the ability for Spin Bash to skip to the WA extension.\n- Decreased startup on 1h Greathammer and 1h Pickaxe R1s from 24 frames to 20 frames. \n- Decreased recovery on 1h Greathammer and 1h Pickaxe R1s by 5 frames. \n- Changed the 1h Greathammer second R1 to the 1h Pickaxe second R1. \n- Decreased recovery on Pickaxe 2h R1 by 4 frames. \n- Offhand first R1 for Greathammers and Pickaxe has the same frame data as the mainhand first R1. \n\n- Quakestone Hammer can now be buffed.\n- Reduced scaling on Mace when infused with Blessed. \n- Changed the Rolling R1 for Ledo’s Greathammer when buffed with WA to match that of other Greathammers. \n\nKatanas\n- Increased Strength scaling on Black Blade. \n- Lowered Dexterity requirement on Black Blade to 16. \n- Increased recovery to Forward R2 from Running R1 on 2h Katanas.\n\nScythes\n- 2h Lothric Scythe and Pontiff Knight Great Scythe both have the Curved Greatsword/Reaper kick attack.\n- Increased R1/R2 buffer window for Neck Swipe WA. \n\nSpears &amp; Pikes\n- Spears shieldpoke is now as fast as Thrusting Sword shieldpoke. \n- Removed the ability for Pikes to feint the Running R1. \n\nStraight Swords\n- Made the transition from 1h and 2h charged R2s with Dark Sword to uncharged R2s faster by 3 frames. \n- Reduced motion value of Straight Sword stance WA R2 to vanilla. \n- Returned original moveset to Irithyll Straight Sword.\n- Altered moveset of Silver Knight Straight Sword. \n- Shortsword, Broadsword and Broken Straight Sword have unique, faster 2h R1s. \n- Reduced AR of Shortsword and Broadsword.\n- Improved tracking of 2h Valorheart Forward R2. \n- Changed the health regen of Anri’s Straight Sword from 2 HP every 2 seconds to 2 HP every 4 seconds. \n- Removed the ability for Lothric Knight Sword to feint R2 into Stance. \n\nThrusting Swords \n- Irithyll Rapier has a new weapon art. \n\nWhips\n- Witch&apos;s Locks can now perform backstabs and ripostes. \n\nSpells\n- Black Serpent can no longer feint. \n- Black Serpent recovery increased by 5 frames.\n\n- Lifehunt Scythe can be turned while casting.\n\n- Way of White Corona now fires 5 projectiles in front.\n- Increased motion value of Way of White Corona projectiles from 85 to 100.\n- Increased stamina damage of Way of White Corona projectiles from 30 stamina to 60 stamina.\n- Increased the duration for which thrown Way of White Corona projectiles linger before returning to the caster. \n\n- Healing spells have an additional effect. Regain HP through consecutive attacks. This effect has a duration of 20 seconds. \n\nCatalysts &amp; Staves\n- Staves can now perform Forward R2s. \n- Staves now have new R2 chains. \n- Murky Longstaff has special effects during swing animations. \n\n\nBug Fixes\n---------------\n\n- Sacred Bloom Shield no longer has a bug causing it to perform the Silver Knight Straight Sword WA. \n- Fixed Thrusting Sword parry animation. \n- Fixed a bug where charged 2h Curved Sword R2s had the Moonlight Greatsword sound effect. \n- Fixed clipping issue with Footman’s Hood. \n- Fixed animation issue with Lothric Scythe caused by not meeting the requirements. \n- Fixed a bug with Greatshield hitboxes. \n- Resolved a bug where offhand hybrid catalysts would trigger mainhand catalyst spells when pressing L2. \n- Using Siegbrau no longer consumes stamina.</notes>
	</n5>
	<n4>
		<version>1.2.1</version>
		<notes>- Added simplified Chinese in-game item descriptions (thanks Nep.Bin)</notes>
	</n4>
	<n3>
		<version>1.2</version>
		<notes>- Estus and Ashen stamina cost reverted back to normal\n- offhand rotten ghru doesn't block anymore\n- offhand murkey doesn't use shield attacks \n- Fixed parrying dagger offhand\n- Fixed crossbow reload back to vanilla \n- Irithyll SS and SKSS don't have poise for 2h \n- Fixed issue where you can recovery cancel offhand attacks \n- Fixed issue where certain stance attacks don't come out fast enough \n- Fixed quickstep glitch and now it stuns properly \n- Changed harald/mechete firt r1s \n- Nerfed shields damage and block frames\n- Fixed parry frames for crow quills \n- bows that had puncture as weapon art now use puncture all the time as normal arrow \n- composite/short bows have faster r1 to r1 bow \n- pharis is able to fire 3 arrows from normal r1s/r2s \n- ledos when buffed now can feint</notes>
	</n3>
	<n2>
		<version>1.1</version>
		<notes>New changes\n----------------\n\n- Complete overhaul with offhand mechanic\n   - All weapons have L1 as the chain combo \n   - All weapons allow weapon skill similar to shields except:\n      - Crystal sage/rapier: these have an offhand running attack for L2\n      - Crow quills: L2 uses new improved parry \n      - Scimitar, ghru, pkcs: These have an offhand running attack for l2 \n      - Painted guardian: kept the parry for l2 \n      - Claws/fist: still parry \n- As a result of previous change, Barefists were reverted back to vanilla AR and scaling \n- Thrusting Halberds gained Shieldpoke \n- Estus now takes you to negative stamina and caps at negative 60. You can still chug multiple estus regardless of stamina\n- Ashen estus cost 30 stamina \n- Gave silver knight SS new R1s matching its Dks1 counterpart while also having better synergy to WA than normal ss r1s and able to panic roll catch on 3rd r1\n- New moveset for broadsword and improved its HA to Hammer level when 2h \n- Dragonslayer Axe Gained lightning strike WA\n- Drakeblood GS Gained Lightning strike WA\n- Silver knight spear WA r1 reduced stamina consumption by half \n- Harald CGS gained a new moveset\n- Great Machete Gained a new moveset \n- Butcher’s knife gained a new weapon art executioner's stomp \n- Irithyll SS gained a new moveset and a new spin slash that shoots Ice at the end of it\n- Lorian GS gained Dimension Strike WA and increased its innate fire slightly for losing buff \n- Lothric scythe got much more fitting overall moveset\n- Lothric scythe Gained R2 feint as well on WA and improved its feint window\n- Replaced 3 gestures into dark souls 1 gestures\n   - Point down to “Triple point down” \n   - Welcome to “well what is it” \n   - Point up to “Look skyward” \n- Kick buffer window made 10frames before active frame \n- All forms of stances (hold, rapier stance etc) weapon arts got reduction to FP cost \n- Stance WA r2 for GS and SS got improved MV \n- Pontiff Scythe gained a new kick when two handed\n- Removed poise from SKSS WA \n- Nerfed poise start up, fp consumption, and wa to wa cancel of caestus WA\n- Replaced Vordt WA to Champion’s Charge\n- Nerfed WA to WA and tracking of immolation tinder Weapon art \n- Crossbow reload is now back to vanilla \n- Adjusted tracking on r1s of Vertical UGS, GA, and Scythes to have better tracking than vanilla if unlocked but now are straffable if they attack lock on \n- Nerfed Wolf GS wa r2 tracking \n- Nerfed Black knight GS wa tracking\n- Improved Follower Javalin’s HA \n- Havel shield gained shield bash\n- Bowglitch fixed both mainhand and offhand by change all weapon art into quickstep \n- Bows can be equipped offhand now\n- Improved Bows overall recovery significantly \n- Only bows have quickstep and it function different than vanilla where it has no iframe but it has HA, damage reduction, and a stagger stun if bump into people with quickstep \n- Rapier wa r1 feint cost stamina and its MV decreased to normal r1 level\n- Rapier wa r2 motion value increased  \n- Added R1/r2 feints sword of judgment WA R2\n- Decreased Gotthard and onkiri 2h r1s tracking\n- Improved poise level for 2h forward r2 of scythes and halberd \n- Improved follower WA tracking slighly and gave it its extension R1/r2 cancels \n- Black knight GA gained a new kick when two handed\n- Gave all form of spin slashes ability to skip to 2nd r1 using wa to r1 cancel from 0 to 5 frames window \n- Improved Astora’s base AR slightly and removed its 12 faith requirement \n- Made Shield 2h r1s chain better due to better range \n- Greatshields gained new jumping attacks\n- Improved 2h thrusting halberd speed\n- Improved offhand synergy with main hand on utilities that allow weapon skill\n\n\nFixed bugs\n-------------\n\n- Fixed Lothric scythe not being able to backstab\n- Fixed irithyll SS not being able to backstab\n- Fixed Harald CGS not being able to backstab\n- Fixed makoto parry animation when 1h \n- Fixed PKCS no FP issue\n- Fixed Millwood wa to r1 not comboing properly \n- Fixed issue where 1h forward r2 does not have hitbox for frayed blade\n- Harpe and crescent CS only get buff outside of the feint window\n- Removed dagger infinite \n- Fixed 2h running dagger roll cancel\n- Fixed caestus bullet’s lightning effect\n- Fixed Salvation axes sorting sorting issue in the menu\n- Slowed fire whip down a little to fix huge damage true combos\n- Souls stream’s infinite issue \n- Fixed issue where yorshka/crystal chime didnt have stamina cost\n- Fixed issue where heavy cs had ss stun on 2h backswings \n- Fixed issue where offhand sorcery casting didn't feint \n- Fixed red hilted T-pose issue\n- Fixed immolation tinder farron flash sword no hitstun issue \n- Fixed issue where great chaos cost more stamina than vanilla \n- Fixed issue where fume and other ugs do the wrong push for 2h full charge r2s \n- Fixed no fp lothric doing wrong throw/push instead of pancake\n- Fixed greatshield shieldbash to now use stamina when feint instead of fp</notes>
	</n2>
	<n1>
		<version>1.0</version>
		<notes>First public release on nexusmods.</notes>
	</n1>
</UpdateNotes>
